Chapter 6: Whitewashed Secrets

Author's Notes: I noticed today that fanfiction lets you make a cover image for your story, so I made one in about 30 seconds on the gimp. It's not very good. If anyone wants to make a better one (really, almost anything would be better) just let me know.

There's some stuff happening next week, so the next chapter will be short and/or late.

Today's Character Sheet: myth-weavers com/sheetview php?sheetid=586163

Milo slipped through the doors to Lockhart's office, aware that he would be largely helpless if the famous wizard had left any magical traps in case of intruders. While Milo's instincts told him this was unlikely—most magical traps he could name took hours or days to set up, and Lockhart had only just arrived at the school—he reminded himself that wanded magic could at times be unpredictable. Not that there was really much he could do about it.

He wasn't certain what he expected to find, which, in his experience, was generally a good enough reason to investigate something.

While Lockhart appeared to have only been in this office long enough to drop off his luggage (or, more likely, had a fan or house elf carry it for him), there was already a pile of mail in the centre of the floor that reached Milo's shoulders. No wonder the employees at the owl post office looked so stressed, Milo thought. Probably half the mail in magical Britain goes to Lockhart.

"Scholar's Touch," Milo muttered, tapping eight letters more-or-less at random. All eight were fan mail with no discernible secret code (of which Milo was something of an expert, considering all of his Ranks in the frustratingly-underused Decipher Script skill. He hadn't yet found anything worth deciphering since he brilliantly deduced that 'Erised' was 'Desire' written back-to-front). Still, that wasn't to say that there wasn't something incriminating in there somewhere. However, it would take all of Milo's magic for weeks to Scholar's Touch the whole pile—not to mention all the library books he still had to read.

This was not to say that Milo was out of tricks, however.

"Spontaneous Search, Master's Touch." The two spells together allowed him to thoroughly search Lockhart's entire office in the blink of an eye, much as he had done to help Neville find his toad the first time he'd boarded the Hogwarts' Express.

This time, instead of discovering a toad, Milo was presented with a catalogue of all of the Defence Professor's worldly possessions; unfortunately, nothing was terribly suspicious except for the staggering number of mirrors and pictures of himself that the professor had brought with him. All that confirmed, however, was that Lockhart was unlikely to be a vampire (unless, of course, this was a piece of cunning misinformation). Perhaps Mordy could have smelled something, but Milo had left him in the Great Hall to keep an eye on the Sorting for him.

"Dammit!" Milo muttered. He was so sure that he was on to something, sneaking here. He was beyond desperation at this point. He had to know what was happening or it would drive him mad. "Detect Weaponry, Treasure Scent, Locate Water, Locate City, Detect Ship." He knew he was stretching probability there towards the end, but after each successive lack of suspicious results, he cast every type of spell he could think of that could tell him anything. All he succeeded in, however, was discovering that the silver frames of Lockhart's portraits were false and that Flitwick, whose office was nearby, was the proud owner of a model man-of-war.

It was then that the door opened.

Milo, his heart racing, pressed himself as flatly up against the wall as he could, counting on his Invisibility to hide him.

Milo felt his breath catch as the Potions Master skulked into the office. The Potions Master peered around suspiciously, then closed the door behind him. He took a quick look around, his eyes lingering on the pile of fan correspondence and his mouth twisted into a sneer of contempt.

Once he appeared convinced that nobody was present, he drew his wand. Milo tensed up, readying himself (but not Readying; he'd learned his lesson) to react quickly and decisively, if necessary. He'd had enough unfortunate encounters with the professor as it stood.

Snape muttered the incantation to a spell that Milo couldn't catch, aiming his wand at the pile of Lockhart's luggage. The bags and cases unbuttoned, unzipped, and unlatched themselves (as appropriate), and their contents floated up into the air, all clearly visible. Snape ran his eyes over the clothes, paintings, various hair products, and books—mostly copies of his autobiography, Magical Me—before shoving them back into the cases with magic. While they had been quite neatly sorted and folded initially, Snape's spell left them a jumbled mess. The bags and cases buttoned, zipped, and latched themselves (as appropriate) before returning to their approximate locations. Evidently disappointed, Snape turned and left, his black cloak trailing behind him.

"Phew," Milo said, releasing his breath. "That was close." He waited for about a minute, then left as well. With his handle on the door, Milo gave the room one last look, knowing it was largely futile. Anything hiding in there that had escaped his Divinations would have to have been hidden by an individual of unrivalled skill, if not the gods themselves.

o—o

A few minutes after he heard Milo leave, George strolled out of Lockhart's office casually. Shortly after, a large number of dungbombs detonated simultaneously.

o—o—o—o

Judging by the crowds leaving the Great Hall, Milo had missed the Sorting Ceremony altogether. While his stomach disagreed, Milo considered it a price well worth paying. He hadn't discovered much about Lockhart—except that Snape also considered him suspect. Milo gathered that Snape had had similar thoughts about Quirrell, and, despite all evidence practically proving his evilness, had Dumbledore's trust. Could Dumbledore have asked Snape to investigate Lockhart? Or was Snape simply paranoid as a matter of course?

Still, it was shaky. Milo needed something concrete, something obvious...

A shrill scream echoed through the Hogwarts hallways.

Perfect!

Milo broke into a sprint. He didn't know what had happened, who had done it, or who it had happened to, but one thing was for sure: it was a hook. And maybe someone was in danger. Either way, he had to get there fast. He considered using Dimension Door to teleport to general area the from which scream had originated, but he'd used so many spells searching Lockhart's office, not to mention multiple castings of Invisibility, that he thought he ought to save them in case of trouble. He was moving at such a breakneck pace that when he rounded a corner and stepped in some sort of liquid, he lost his balance and fell, sliding several feet before hitting a wall.

Surprisingly—he'd been expecting blood—he was lying in a pool of whitewash.

It was then that he realized he'd been had.

"Gods dammit, Peeves!" he roared. He could hardly remember being so frustrated in his life. He sat up, hitting his head on something unexpected and hard.

Milo looked up after the flash of pain subsided, and was surprised to see a bucket. He was even more surprised to see the holder of the bucket, once full of the whitewash that was now covering Milo's robes. Unsurprisingly, it was Peeves, but he appeared, well... stiff. Immobile. It was jarring. Peeves, as a poltergeist, was a being of chaos—he embodied unpredictability, movement, change.

"The hell?" Milo muttered, looking closer, ready in case this was some sort of elaborate prank. It only took a single look at Peeves' face to see that it wasn't. His unmoving features were locked in an expression of pure terror.

Milo waved a hand back and forth in front of Peeves, but there was no response. He narrowed his eyes.

Interesting, Milo thought. As a spirit, I'd just assumed Peeves was immune to most status effects. If he ever wakes up from whatever-this-is, and drops feathers on me again...

It was perhaps due to fate, the will of the gods, or simply poor luck that Milo was discovered by a group of Slytherin first years, fresh from Sorting, coated in white paint and cackling like a lunatic over what appeared to be a terrified, unmoving little man dressed as a clown.

Worse, perhaps, was the foot-high writing in blood on the wall behind him that he'd completely failed to notice, having focussed so much on the Petrified poltergeist.

THE CHAMBER OF SECRETS HAS BEEN OPENED.

ENEMIES OF THE HEIR, BEWARE.

"Ah, crap," Milo muttered.

o—o—o—o

"September 7th, 1992," Fiona said to the recorder. "I have become aware that my memory may have been tampered with, and it might not be the first time..." She went on to detail the events of her insane day. Whoever had messed with her head (who she'd privately termed 'Loki'), she'd realized, clearly had only a scanty knowledge at best of technology. They'd confused the computer monitor with the computer itself—admittedly, a difference she herself had only come to be aware of as a result of Loki's botched intervention. As such, she'd decided to keep records on tape wherever possible rather than on paper. She'd considered getting a computer for herself, but a single look at the prices had disabused her of that notion; a sergeant's pay could only go so far.

She didn't know who or what Loki was. That had frightened her, at first. The idea of a shady, covert being out there with the power to alter another's memories was, frankly, terrifying. For all she knew, she'd already been affected by his/her/their/its abilities dozens or hundreds of times. Loki could be in the room with her right now, altering her memories in real time.

That's what she'd thought at first. The mistake with the Machine proved that Loki wasn't infallible, and she could exploit that.

She had to. It was her duty; she'd sworn an oath. For the Queen, for the people of England, for the residents of Surrey, and for herself. Nobody damn well messes with my head and walks.

And so she'd made a plan.

o—o—o—o

Lkoturo was in the comfortable position of a man who had everything. And a man who has everything could go wherever he pleased.

Lkoturo threw one last look in the mirror. True, his meeting with the aging emperor was supposed to have started three minutes ago, but it never hurt to remind him who was really in charge. Excellent, he thought. He'd decided to indulge a little and broke out his best goatee wax. It was expensive—mermaid scales don't come cheap—but worth every gold piece. Because, Lkoturo reminded himself, he was worth it.

Zuzu, his familiar, fluttered up beside him, his dull purple scales shining in the candlelight.

"Master," the imp hissed. "The Watch has caught another team of self-proclaimed heroes in the act. A charge of Illegal Vigilante Justice, Wealth Grossly Exceeding Official WBL Mandate, Grand Theft Arcana, and Resisting Arrest for each."

"Excellent," Lkoturo said happily. Everything really was coming up his way, for once. "And how's the bandit situation?"

"They're still operating in the countryside largely unhindered," Zuzu said. "The Watch has its hands full keeping the adventurers in check. They simply can't spare the men to hunt them down."

"Perfect," Lkoturo practically purred, admiring his goatee once more. The mermaid wax gave it a shine that other types simply couldn't compete with. Despite what the Druids claimed, it was harvested in a completely humane method—the mermaids weren't using those scales, anyway; the dark reaver powder saw to that. "And the sewers?"

"We're having a bit more trouble with that," Zuzu said. "Keeping the kobold population high enough to remain a threat is difficult; they keep being killed by the rats."

"Well, you can't win them all. At least the rats are gaining experience, I presume?"

"Indeed. Some even appear to be adopting PC classes."

"Fascinating. Keep me updated."

"As always, my lord."

"And now, I suppose, I must go see the emperor." Lkoturo walked down the short corridor leading from his chambers to the royal ones. Of course, in the tradition of most viziers, he had a number of more... discreet entrances to the emperor's rooms. How else would he spy on, enchant, and, when necessary, poison the reigning monarch? That said, he preferred to use the regular hallways whenever possible, just to keep up the illusion of requiring them. He paused in front of the emperor's doorway and adjusted his cloak. A pair of guards in immaculately polished full plate carrying halberds guarded the door, but he didn't care what they saw—they were so full of Enchantments that they were essentially very pretty, menacing pieces of furniture.

He moved his hand slightly, and the guards threw open the doors to the emperor's 'private' study (Lkoturo had no less than six wall paintings with the eyes cut out that he could peer through for when he didn't want to waste a Clairaudience or Scry spell). The emperor sat behind his desk, staring through a window at Myra absently. Like the palace guards, the emperor hadn't had an independent thought in years.

"You summoned me, sire?" Lkoturo said in his oiliest voice, bowing so low his hat almost touched the ground. It was only when the doors closed behind him that he realized they weren't alone. A thin, almost starved-looking woman with a tangle of black hair stood near the window. A quick Knowledge check identified her as human, not that that was any indicator of threat. Her Class and Level were completely unknown. He recovered from his surprise quickly. "And who might you be?" Lkoturo was hardly defenceless—like any good Grand Vizier, he had a number of Contingent spells in case of emergency, most of which were designed to fake his own death while Teleporting him to safety, or, if he did in fact die, level the building as an act of revenge while he safely awoke in a Cloned body in a secure location. That said, he didn't have an adventurer's assurance of only fighting level-appropriate encounters. She could be anyone from a poor homeless woman to an epic Sorceress to the avatar of Vecna.

"And who might you be," she said in a mocking tone.

It took Lkoturo the duration of a blink to make his decision. "Guards!" he shouted."Guards!"

"Guards, guards," the woman said in the same tone. "Look at him; ordering the poor Muggles about as if they were still his. Guards, guards."

"I don't know who you are, but if you're willing to talk, I'm sure we can come to some sort of mutual under—Disintegr—"

A wand appeared in the woman's hand as if it had Teleported there. "Silencio." Lkoturo's mouth moved, but no sound came out. The spell failed. He couldn't believe it—using Silence to counter a spell was common enough, but his Spellcraft told him that that wasn't a spell. The woman clearly had no idea how to use a wand, but even if she had it wouldn't have helped; the stick she was holding was just that—a stick. No matter.

Silent Flesh to St—

The woman flicked her wand with a carefully practiced-looking manoeuvre and suddenly Lkoturo found himself pressed against the wall by unseen forces—once again, no magic to be seen.

"You people are all so predictable," she said, suddenly deadly serious. The rapid change of expression was unnerving, all the more so because he was pretty certain her facial features hadn't really moved, they'd just... changed in meaning somehow. Looking at her made him regret taking ranks in Sense Motive; she was very clearly insane. "The first thing you do after being silenced is to cast a nonverbal spell of some variety; never to flee."

Good idea, Lkoturo thought. Silent Dimension Do—

"And another thing; you always start casting every six seconds exactly. Like clockwork. Imperio."

o—o—o—o

The screaming Slytherins had, of course, attracted attention. Professors Snape, Dumbledore, McGonagall, and Lockhart gathered around Peeves and the writing. A crowd of students clustered around behind them, some frightened but most simply curious.

"Well," said Snape, "I can't say it's any great loss."

"Oh, he'll be fine," McGonagall said, somewhat bitterly. "Poltergeists are quite indestructible—believe me; I know. What I am more concerned about is..." she gestured at the writing on the wall.

"This is exactly like what happened once in a village near Thiruvananthapuram," Lockhart interjected. "Of course, I'm sure you've read all about it in Magical Me, but it turned out to be nothing more than a disgruntled hag and a pair of goblins. Fascinating story, you know, they nearly dunked me head-first in Screaming Snakes Hair Potion, but, cleverly, I flashed the hag my best smile and she fell for me at once. Getting away from her, as it turned out, was almost as difficult..."

"Really?" said Professor McGonagall. "Because that doesn't sound terribly similar at all, Gilderoy."

"Well, when I say exactly, I mean it has certain resemblances that appear once you scratch the surface," Lockhart replied, completely unfazed. "For example, both encounters prominently feature a small man in a clown costume, but admittedly, the one which I encountered was revealed, in a stunning twist, to be five gnomes standing on each other's heads."

"If only a similar discovery could be made about Peeves," Snape said. "In the mean time, I believe it would be prudent to send these students on their way and have this mess cleaned up?"

"Indeed, Severus," Dumbledore said absently. "Minerva? If you would be so kind?"

"Of course, Albus," McGonagall said, then turned to the students. "You heard the Headmaster, everyone! Back to your common rooms—that means you, Mister Weasley!"

"I'm George!"

"I never said otherwise." McGonagall narrowed her eyes, and the students scattered. Once again, Milo found himself forced to respect the Transfiguration Professor's abilities of Intimidation.

o—o—o—o

Gilderoy Lockhart had always prided himself on his neatness and attention to detail; both, indeed, were a requirement for his line of work. So, when he entered his office that evening, he immediately knew something was awry, and it wasn't just the smell of dungbombs. He'd expected that—likely some young wizard was jealous of his success and good looks. No, it was the contents of his suitcase, all in complete disarray.

A thorough search (after, of course, using a powerful Air-Purifying Charm to deal with the smell) revealed that nothing had been stolen, so someone had merely... searched his belongings? Who? Why? Could someone know his secret? Or did they merely suspect?

He'd expected this to be a soft, easy gig, but it appeared that he would have to keep his guard up.

o—o—o—o

With her shift over, Fiona, now in plainclothes, approached what appeared to be the most soulless residence she'd ever seen. She expected it to seem eerily familiar, as if she'd seen it once in a dream, but it didn't. It just looked, well, ordinary. Oppressively so, in fact; it was as if whoever resided there (she hesitated to use the word "lived," for there was clearly no life to be had in this house) desperately wanted to blend in.

That was the first thing that made her suspicious.

She knocked. Once.

Before her knuckles touched the door the second time, it opened.

"Yes? Hello? What do you want?" said a short, overweight man with a noticeable lack of manners, style, or neck.

"Sergeant Fiona Smythe, Surrey Police," she said coolly. Just because this wasn't exactly an official visit didn't mean that she couldn't introduce herself as a police officer. As far as she knew. She was a police officer.

The man's mannerisms changed almost at once. "Oh, of course, officer," he said in an oily manner, "what can I do for you?"

"Vernon Dursley?" Fiona took the man's mute fear as an affirmative. "I'm here following up on the disturbance that occurred here on the 31st of July."

Vernon froze.

That was the second thing that made her suspicious.

"Which disturbance was that, exactly?"

"I understood an armed, extremely disturbed minor entered your house and damaged some of your property?"

"You must be mistaken," Vernon said through clenched teeth. "We certainly have no disturbed minors on this premises. Oh, no. None at all. Never have, in fact."

"I see. Then I must have been mistaken. Thank you for your time."

Vernon slammed the door shut in her face.

Well, well, well... she thought. Vernon clearly remembered what had happened; he was a terrible liar. And it just as clearly had happened—the paint on the window pane in front of the dining room was fresh.

That was the third thing that made her suspicious.

So either Mr. Dursley here was involved, or intimidated somehow. There was only one thing to do now, and that was go door-to-door. Maybe one of the neighbours had seen something.

o—o—o—o—o—o—o

D&D Tip #1: You know how Milo can Shatter wands and render wizards helpless? You can do that in D&D, too! If you destroy or steal (say by Shatter, Sunder, or Sleight of Hand) a Cleric's Holy Symbol, a Wizard's Spell Component Pouch, or a Druid's Holly and Mistletoe, that caster is now an Expert, Commoner, or Grizzly Bear, respectively.

D&D Tip #2: Speaking of Sleight of Hand, it's a DC 20 check to swipe something from another character. This is a fixed DC. That means that pick-pocketing Pelor is just as easy as pick-pocketing the city watch (caveat the first: the higher the target's level, the harder it is to get away with that without getting caught. So if you pick pocket Pelor, hope you have your smite-resistant pants on). You can take a -20 penalty to make a pick pocket attempt as a free action. You can do infinite free actions per round, so, if you can make a DC 40 Sleight of Hand check (even if it's only on a 20) then you can brute force every single item off of your mark on your turn. Curiously, this doesn't include 'sheathed weapons,' which have an insane DC of 50 (70 as a free action). You also can't steal held items, which takes a Disarm attempt. However, you can probably steal:

-Clothes, armour, etc.

-Wands, potions, etc.

-Many, many coins

-Holy symbols, spell component pouches, and the like

-Artifacts of Doom

(caveat the second: don't actually use this trick. It breaks the game in an un-fun way, and in any case, the 'infinite free actions' thing is kind of a myth—the rule is that you have a 'reasonable' number of free actions.)

Chapter 8: Gilderoy Lockhart

Author's Notes: Good news, everyone! Harry Potter and the Natural 20 has inspired its first story, a Dune/D&D crossover by DalkonCledwin! It's only in its first chapter, but The Won Initiative and the Kwisatz Haderach can be found here on fanfiction (links are blocked, but you can find it with a quick search). It has a very promising beginning, so you should all check it out and show DalkonCledwin some support.

Here's the blurb: While traveling on a Spelljammer, our Hero Argylle suddenly gets transported to a far off land where things quickly start to stop making sense to his years of expertise. All the while the people of this new world are continuously baffled by his seemingly superior combat skills and his ability to charm some of the most dangerous creatures their world has to offer...

Update: So my wisdom teeth came out this week, which is getting in the way of my writing somewhat. This week's chapter will probably be late by a couple of days.

Fiona awoke in her bed with a strange feeling well-known to anyone who has ever been jolted awake by dream-tripping on the dream-sidewalk. She spent a few seconds taking deep breaths to calm her racing heart.

"Bloody hate those," she muttered to herself, then checked her alarm clock:

6:33.

"Shit!" She was three minutes behind schedule. She had her entire morning, every morning, planned out to the minute—enough time to put kettle on, throw bread in toaster, hop in shower, get dressed, start tea steeping, feed Sprocket, get toast out of toaster, butter and then eat toast for breakfast, put now-steeped tea in vacuum flask, throw dishes in sink, put shoes on, grab walkman, open door, go out door, close door, lock door, listen to Rolling Stones, jog to station, arrive at station at precisely seven o'clock, start work. She briefly debated which to sacrifice between her morning shower, breakfast, and tea, but was already in the shower with the kettle on before realizing she'd made her decision.

Sprocket—her enormously fat calico cat—was vocally unhappy with this decision, as she usually unabashedly ate any and all crumbs Fiona left behind after breakfast, but sometimes sacrifices had to be made.

Once she was on the street, she, while moving, put her headphones on and pressed play. Rather than Ruby Tuesday, the song she had listened to every morning on the way to work (and on morning jogs on weekends and holidays) for the last four years, she heard her own voice in the recorder.

"If you know why you're hearing yourself speak, hold fast-forward for thirty seconds. No? Still here? Damn, they got you again. Well, anyway, here's what's going on..."

Strangely enough, it was the knowledge that if she stopped to freak out then she'd be late for work that allowed her to, more or less, keep her cool. She listened to herself list out events, locations where she'd stashed notes and journals, and reassurances that this was, unfortunately, not a joke. She realized she was shaking, and it wasn't with fear. How dare they? She didn't know who was behind this, but what gave them the right? Her memories were her own, damn it. They were her life. Taking away someone's memory was murder. The Fiona Smythe who had left this message for her was no less dead just because there was still a Fiona Smythe to listen to it. And this had happened before, no less.

A homeless man approached her, likely to ask for money, but after one look at her face, he just kept on walking.

The tape ended with two very explicit instructions: figure out exactly what you'd done the day before and rewind this cassette.

"No kidding," she muttered, pressing rewind.

o—o—o—o

"Has anybody seen Harry?" Hermione asked, looking around. They were standing in front of the Herbology greenhouses with most of the second-year Hufflepuffs and Gryffindors, waiting for Sprout to arrive and teach them their first Herbology class of the year.

"He was just with us," Ron said, looking around.

Milo frowned. Had Harry somehow been lured away from the group and been Petrified by Slytherin's monster? Had Malfoy finally settled on a plan for revenge and enacted it? Was Harry being lowered slowly into a vat of electric eels? The more he thought about it, the more he was certain the Boy-Who-Lived was once again in mortal peril and needed rescu—

"No, wait, there he is," Ron said.

"Sorry, guys," Harry said. "Would you believe a first-year with a camera tried to get a signed photo of me?"

"A signed photo?" Ron said disgustedly. "You can't let Draco hear about that."

"Believe me, I know."

"Hmm..." Milo said thoughtfully.

"No," Harry said. "I don't know what idea you just had, but I know I won't like it."

"I keep forgetting you're a celebrity here," Milo said. "We could capitalize on that. Harry Potter signed photos, Harry Potter action figures, Harry Potter lunchboxes..."

"Who would want a Harry Potter lunchbox?" Harry scoffed.

"What's more, we should really see if we can get a knut for every Harry Potter Chocolate Frog Card..."

"No. Absolutely not. As if I didn't have enough problems as it is. You wouldn't believe what Lockhart said to me earlier—"

Harry was interrupted by the arrival of Professor Sprout and most of the rest of the Hufflepuffs and Gryffindors.

"We're in Greenhouse Three today," Sprout said cheerfully. "Which means I want everyone on their best behaviour. I haven't had anyone seriously injured in Herbology for more than four years, and that's a streak I don't mean to break." There was an excited murmur among the students—Greenhouse Three held much more dangerous (and, to twelve-year-olds, therefore more interesting) plants than Greenhouse One, which was the only one they had yet entered. "I want everybody in groups of four!" Sprout instructed, which led to a mad dash. Everyone rushed to be with their friends, people in friend circles of five or more raced to not be the odd-man out, and everyone—everyone—tried to discreetly avoid being in Neville's group. They knew who was going to break Sprout's streak if anyone would, and that there might well be collateral damage when he did.

In this whirlwind, Seamus and Dean snatched up Ron and Harry to a distant table, while Milo, who had been distracted, wound up at a table with Hermione, Neville (Milo was glad he was wearing fire-resistant robes) and...

"Hi," Hannah said. "I haven't seen much of you yet. You vanished at the Sorting before I could say hello."

"Hi," Milo said awkwardly. Out of Hannah's line-of-sight, he saw Hermione making mock-gagging motions, followed by exaggeratedly mouthing how was your summer. "How was your summer?" Milo asked. Hermione gave him a thumbs up.

"Oh, you know, the usual. Well, actually, I guess you don't know. Weird. I pretty much spent the summer reading books in my backyard; nothing terribly interesting."

"Well that sounds boring..." Hermione frantically waved her arms in front of her and mouthed No! Bad! "...to boring people," Milo finished. Hermione gave him a hesitant thumbs-up. "I love reading books on the backyard. Just love it. In fact, it's all I ever do..." Hermione gave him a vigorous thumbs-down. "...except when I don't."

"Are you okay?" she asked. "You seem... odd."

"I—"

"We'll be re-potting Mandrakes today," Sprout declared, and all conversation ceased. Sprout was a sweet and cheerful person, but she came down like a dire badger on anyone who talked while she was teaching. "Now, who can tell me the properties of a Mandrake?"

To nobody's surprise, Hermione's hand shot into the air. To everybody's surprise, so did Ron's.

"Very well," said Professor Sprout, slightly taken aback. "Mister Weasley?"

"Mandrakes are the only known cure for Petrification," Ron said proudly.

"Correct," Sprout said. "Ten points for Gryffindor." Milo saw Harry and Ron high-five over at their table. "Mandrake roots can return those who have been transfigured—which includes Petrification—to their original state. As such, it is a vital component to many forms of antidotes. It is also extremely rare—we are quite fortunate to have them here at all. I want everyone to be very careful with them, because in addition to being rare, they are also quite dangerous. Can anyone tell me why?"

Hermione's hand shot up so fast it practically quivered.

"The cry of the Mandrake is fatal to anyone who hears it," she said.

"Precisely. Another ten points for Gryffindor," said Professor Sprout. "Now, these Mandrakes are very young, so their cry won't kill you—it will only knock you out for most of a day. Still, I doubt any of you would want to miss your first day of classes, or that your teachers would be particularly happy with me if you did." Sprout handed out heavy-duty earmuffs to the class, telling them that she would give a thumbs-down when they were allowed to take them off.

Something went 'click' in Milo's brain, but he wasn't sure what it was. It wasn't the obvious thing—that the teachers had realized that more Petrifications were on the way and wanted a remedy in advance. There was also a nagging fear that he'd been mishearing 'mandrake' this entire time, because, after all—the cry of the mandrake? How did a harmless plant cry? Had they been saying 'Man-Drake' this whole time, and there was really some variety of young half-dragon living in this greenhouse? But that was aside from what Milo's hindbrain—for once, he was fairly sure it was not his plot-senses—picked up. Something about young Mandrakes knocking people out...

"Earmuffs on, everybody!" Sprout said happily. Milo didn't need to be told twice. What Sprout pulled out of her pot resembled less the harmless, vaguely humanoid-shaped root that Milo was familiar with, and more a Druid's bogun. It had pale green, mottled skin and judging by the movements of its mouth, it was screaming for all it was worth.

"Boccob," Milo muttered under his breath, not that anyone could hear him. This world continued to surprise him.

When it came time for them to plant their Mandrakes, Milo was glad for his dragonhide gloves. The little plant-things fought for all they were worth not to be put back in their pots. For what Milo was certain would not be the last time, he wished he was a Druid. Then he'd walk out of here with an army of instant-death-causing plant people who lived to do his bidding. Unfortunately, he was not a Druid. He was a Wizard. And sometimes being a Wizard meant getting your hands dirty and not getting any class features.

By the end of the class, everyone was covered in mud, sweat, and, in some cases, Mandrake spit. Sprout assured them it wasn't poisonous, but Neville was starting to develop a concerning-looking rash. Worse, the class had run overtime while they chased down the last Mandrake, who had made a run for his life. They were already late for Transfigurations.

"Prestidigitation," Milo muttered, cleaning himself off.

Transfigurations was predictably dreadful. McGonagall was extremely disappointed that, despite his impressive showing for the Transfiguration exam—he had no intention of telling her how he'd managed to get an 'O' on that—he was unable to transform a beetle into a button. Because the beetle was a living creature, he was unable even to use his Prestidigitation trick. In the end, she'd discreetly suggested he recommence his remedial Transfiguration classes with her on Thursdays after class.

"I don't understand why you don't just tell her," Hannah said afterwards, during their lunch break. "It's the worst-kept secret in school that you're not a normal wizard."

"The way I see it, it's sort of a... polite fiction, you know? As long as it isn't officially acknowledged, there won't be any official action. Transfiguration is a mandatory course until our OWLs, in any case, so it'd look suspicious if I was pulled out. And if McGonagall did find out... I mean, the only other option—aside from dropping the course, that is—is that she'd, you know, help me cheat. Does that seem like something McGonagall would do?"

"No," Hannah said. "But I also don't think she'd support torturing a student who was physically unable to perform even simple Transfigurations this way."

"I still think I can do it," Milo insisted. "I just have to be more creative."

"Why don't you do what you did for the exam?" she asked. "By the way, what did you do for that exam?"

Milo chewed his lip. On the one hand, more people in the loop meant a larger chance of the authorities finding out, but on the other hand, it was pure genius.

"Promise not to tell anyone?" he asked.

"Of course."

"Well," he said conspiratorially, "you see, I—"

It was then that Harry and Ron arrived.

"Oh, hey Milo, Hannah," Harry said. "What's up?"

"Oh, Milo was just about to tell me—Ow!" Milo stepped on her toe. "About, er, you know, the Goblin Uprisings of 1216."

"Wasn't it the Goblin Uprisings of 1612?" Harry asked curiously.

"Well, you know goblins," Milo said with a fake laugh. "They sure do love to rise up, am I right?"

"Well, yeah," Ron agreed. "They do tend to do that a lot."

"So," Milo said, desperately casting about for a change in subject. "How about that, er, Herbology?"

"It was dreadful," Hannah said. "I felt like I was burying little babies alive. Babies that fought like tigers."

"Oh, I dunno," Ron shrugged. "It wasn't so bad for us. Turns out Dean and Seamus—"

"That's how you say his name?" Milo gasped. "That's unfair! They are not allowed to be Seamus and Dean. They can be See-mus and Deen or Shay-mus and Dayne, but they can't have it both ways."

"...Anyway," Ron continued. "They're much better at Herbology than you'd have thought. They really shoved those Mandrakes into those pots like it was nobody's business."

"Very efficient," Harry commented. "No-nonsense whatsoever."

"Huh. I wouldn't have guessed by looking at them," Milo said. "I suppose it's a common enough NPC trait, however."

Ron shrugged. "So what was it Milo was going to tell you?" he asked Hannah curiously.

"What I thought about Golden Boy Stop-Heart," Milo interjected. "And how we'll finally be able to get the measure of him in his class. Which we have now."

"What? We've still got like ten minutes."

"Exactly! We have a new professor, so we can arrive early and, er, make a good impression."

Ron paused. "Who are you and what did Hermione do with the real Milo?"

"I am the real Milo. Now are you coming, or not?"

"Nah," Ron said. "I'll catch up later. In for a game of Wizard's Chess, Harry?"

"Sure," Harry answered, "but we play by Milo's rules. You only won the last one because your pawn rolled nothing but twenties against my knight."

"Fine," Ron agreed. "But you owe me a round of normal Wizard's Chess later.

"I'll go," Hannah said.

And that was how Milo wound up sitting front-and-centre at Lockhart's first class, wedged between Hermione and Hannah. The classroom was designed to hold a much larger class than the eleven Gryffindor second-years currently present, as some Defence Professors had preferred to teach two or even all four houses simultaneously. As such, there were dozens of empty chairs, so the Gryffindors, as students are wont to do, dispersed to fill all available space equally, rather like a gas. In this case, a lighter-than-air gas, as there were four empty rows behind the three of them before reaching the first outliers higher up the steps.

It was then that Lockhart entered. As always, his hair, smile, and clothes were perfect. This was obvious even to Milo's outsider's perspective.

It occurred to Milo that few people were ever perpetually calm, cheerful, and confident—except for some NPCs, particularly minor ones with little personality. From this he could conclude that Lockhart was either an exceptional actor or a flat character. Time would tell which was true; largely by the amount of detail his character warranted and how much time was spent on him.

It was then that Milo began counting adjectives.

"Me," Lockhart said, pointing at his own smiling portrait on the covers of their textbooks. "Gilderoy Lockhart, Order of Merlin, Third Class, Honorary Member of the Dark Force Defence League and five times winner of Witch Weekly's Most-Charming-Smile award—but I don't talk about that. I didn't get rid of the Bandon Banshee by smiling at her!"

There were a few scattered laughs from the audience. Milo was simply floored. He'd had his suspicions about Lockhart, of course—especially considering what happened with the last Defence Professor. But he'd never thought that the first words out of the man's mouth that were directed to their class would be a simple list of facts describing himself. In valuable time that a Professor could be using for exposition—much like Sprout had, for example—Lockhart did nothing but draw attention to his own talents. It was not the most subtle thing he had ever seen the DM (Detail Magnet) point out to him before. Milo began taking notes frantically.

"I see you've all bought a complete set of my books—well done. I thought we'd start today with a little quiz. Nothing to worry about—just to check how well you've read them, how much you've taken in..."

While Lockhart handed out test papers, Milo surreptitiously reached into his backpack.

"Scholar's Touch," he muttered, tapping Lockhart's various textbooks (half of which were plagiarized bootleg copies he'd made from Ron's). Hermione shot him a disapproving look, but Hannah just chuckled.

"You have thirty minutes. Start—now!"

Milo looked at the sheet, and was glad he'd refreshed his memory. The quiz was full of the most minute trivia: What is Gilderoy Lockhart's secret ambition? What is Gilderoy Lockhart's favourite breed of cat? What is Gilderoy Lockhart's favourite dance? In your experience, how has Gilderoy Lockhart most changed your life? Who is Gilderoy Lockhart's role model? Despite having already read the books with Scholar's Touch before, he'd never have remembered this many details.

Milo quickly realized Gilderoy Lockhart had more backstory than the rest of this setting combined. Gilderoy Lockhart was a more well-rounded, fleshed-out character than he was.

Gilderoy Lockhart was capital-'I' Important.

Half an hour later, Lockhart collected the tests, reading through them and pointing out common errors—his favourite dance was the foxtrot, and his role model was, of course, himself. Then he paused.

"Well, well, well," he said delightedly. "It appears that not one but two of you managed to get a perfect score! Ten points for Gryffindor for each of my devoted admirers. Well done, Mister Amastacia-Liadon and Miss Granger!"

Hermione turned a violent shade of pink, and Milo realized he may have accidentally drawn attention to himself. The chortles from the back row had nothing to do with his embarrassment—at least, he firmly believed that if he told himself that frequently enough, it might become true.

Lockhart then placed a large cage covered in a white sheet on the table. Milo, already somewhat on edge, sat up a little straighter and shook his sleeves clear of his hands. He'd had bad experiences with Defence Professors bringing live monsters to class before.

"I must ask you not to scream," Lockhart said in a stage whisper. "It might provoke them."

It was then that Lockhart released the pixies. Electric blue, slightly over half a foot tall, with voices so shrill that they forced a Will save to avoid becoming severely irritated. As soon as the cage door flipped open, they made a run for it.

"Have no fear!" Lockhart said, drawing his wand. "Peskipiski Pesternomi!" If the spell did anything, however, it was not apparent. The pixies escaped the cage and flew towards the class—of which, Milo was front-and-centre.

Milo's battle-honed instinctive responses took over immediately. As soon as the pixies were released and his Initiative came up, he leapt to his feet, hands making complicated arcane gestures.

"Shadow Conjuration," he cast. Shadow Conjuration was a phenomenally-versatile Illusion spell could mimic any Conjuration spell of up to 3rd level. This made it perfect for casting any one of hundreds of possible spells so circumstantial (Milo liked to think of them as 'use-impaired') that nobody would ever bother preparing them—in this case, Malevolent Miasma.

Ten thin tendrils of grey fog streaked with dark, nauseating patches burst out of Milo's outstretched fingers, splitting up in mid-air into ever-smaller branches that flew down the Pixies' throats. The pixies began choking and fell to the ground, one gasping out a feeble "Crivens!" before succumbing to the effects of the spell. In seconds, they all lay still on the ground, unconscious.

There were many, many more effective spells than Malevolent Miasma, but this one was the first he thought of which had everything he needed—it was nonlethal, affected a small area (he had no intention of ending up in detention for knocking out a Professor on his first day of classes), and fairly long-lasting.

Gods, Milo thought to himself. I am such an idiot. Really, you'd think he'd have learned after the Glitterdust Incident last September. And I'd just beaten myself up for drawing attention to myself... Now I'm going to get the whole Gryffindor House in detention again or something.

If Lockhart was surprised, he hid it well.

"Well done!" he exclaimed. "Young Mister Anastasia-Llewin here passed the test! For, as I'm sure you can now divine, I was testing your responses when faced with danger after an authority figure failed to protect you. Twenty points for Gryffindor!"

Lockhart enlisted a few volunteers to re-cage the pixies, and the rest of the class mostly consisted of Lockhart discussing his various exploits.

"Well," Milo said afterwards. "That was... unexpected."

"The pixies being released?" Ron asked. "Because that was ridiculous. What kind of person releases magical creatures into a group of unsuspecting students?"

"No, I meant Grimlock's clear central importance to the Plot. Also, that I burned a fourth-level spell on those things. With my luck, I'll be ambushed by Acromantula-riding Redcaps later today and run out of spells because of it."

"I think it was clever," Hermione said. "Testing our responses under pressure. Exactly what a good Defence Professor should do. Certainly got my heart racing, that's for sure."

"Pretty sure it was his smile that did that," Ron muttered sotto voce, but Milo didn't think Hermione heard it. All things considered, this was probably fortunate for Ron's ambitions of surviving to adulthood.

"If you ask me, he was completely clueless," Harry said. "I think he expected that spell to work."

"But that doesn't make any sense," Hermione countered. "It's simple logic. Why would he publically rely on a spell he hadn't practiced in advance if he wanted it to work? Besides, I don't think it's even a real spell. It had to have been an act."

"I wonder..." Milo said, "I'm seeing a lot of parallels between him and Fudge. Ambiguously incompetent individuals in positions of extreme fame and power, respectively, who may or may not be putting on an act. Perhaps... perhaps he's Fudge's secret apprentice? Or long-lost child? Maybe he is Fudge, keeping an eye on the school in disguise..."

They continued their debate all the way to Gryffindor Common Room without reaching a consensus. Hermione maintained that he must be a great and powerful wizard—after all, his books said so, and if you can't trust books, who can you trust? Ron and Harry became gradually more certain that Lockhart was a fraud who had somehow bluffed his way into fame, and Milo... Milo was uncertain. There was definitely more to their Defence Professor than appeared on the surface, but the concerning thing was that there was so much surface information. He knew Lockhart's birthday. He didn't even know his own birthday.

Although...

It occurred to Milo that he might be able to do something about that, if he put his mind to it. Like he had with his mother in Dumbledore's office last year.

Not yet, he thought. Part of it was simple pragmatism—it might just happen, someday, that it would be beneficial for him for his birthday to lie on a certain day, and he wouldn't be able to change it once he'd declared it. But there was more than that. It was hard to pin down. Maybe one day, but not today.

Chapter 9: I Scry With My Little Eye

It took four days after Harry's mirror came in the owl post for Milo to realize his error in relying on brute-force Scrying. Harry had ordered the mirror from a specialty furniture shop; it turned out it was more difficult than Milo would have expected to find a mirror that was of 'finely wrought and highly polished silver at least 2 feet by 4 feet' that only cost thirty-seven galleons and some change. As a fourth-level spell, Milo could cast up to four Scrying's per day. With knowledge of the 'Heir of Slytherin' sketchy enough that it didn't even qualify as secondhand, the unknown Heir received a +10 bonus on Will saves to resist the effects. Assuming the Heir had no Wisdom worth mentioning and had a small base save bonus from class (assuming local wizards even had classes, Wisdom, or saving throw bonuses), the Heir had a fifty-percent chance to cause Scrying to fail. Milo very much doubted that the Heir had such a poor Will save bonus. Still, the problem was not insurmountable—there was a five-percent chance for anyone to fail a save, no matter the difficulty. Well, almost anyone. There were a few ways to get around that particular hurdle: Swordsages, for example, could replace some saving throws with Concentration skill checks, which did not have that particular disadvantage. Still, Milo was reasonably confident that, with enough Divinations sent his or her way, eventually the Heir would fail a save.

The problem, however, lay in that 'enough Divinations' part of the plan. Scrying, as it turned out, took a solid hour to cast. While Milo's Dedicated Wright, Cog, shaved off a lot of time Milo would have spent in Item Creation (the little Homunculus was currently working his way through a stack of Amulets of Protection from Evil for the Ministry, in case they ever decided to reply to his letter), there were still the more mundane problems of getting enough sleep to recover spells, doing his homework, and bluffing his way through his classes to worry about.

He'd had to completely suspend all spell research, but not before finishing off Translocation Trick, which allowed him to switch places—and appearances—with someone else. The spell couldn't have been designed better to get him through Potions. He simply followed all of Snape's instructions for the majority of the class, chopping crocodile heart and grinding cockroaches and whatnot as per specifications, then used Translocation Trick to switch places with Ron (who was more than happy to help pull a fast one over Snape) and pretend to reread the instructions for a few seconds while Ron, magically disguised as Milo, stirred the potion as per directions. There a few drawbacks to this plan, however, which was why Milo still spent a fair amount of time brainstorming an improved method. The spell in no way allowed them to sound like the other person, so both he and Ron had to remain perfectly silent for the duration. Further, when the spell ended, they switched back to their original appearances, but not their original locations. Milo originally considered using the simple and low-level Benign Transposition to switch them back, but realized this wouldn't work—they'd still look like each other. Translocation Trick couldn't simply be dismissed like many spells; instead, he had to wait over an hour for it to wear off. As such, Milo was forced to burn not one but two fourth-level spells every Potions class (one to switch places with Ron, another to switch back), which severely hampered his attempts to discover the Heir of Slytherin with magic. Milo smiled ruefully when he remembered Snape's plan last year to oust him for Lucius as a fake wizard by making him brew a potion in front of the Minister for Magic, thinking about how easily he could have foiled the plan if he'd been able to cast fourth-level spells then.

Ironically, since Milo was, when necessary, a meticulous person with a great eye for detail, and the majority of the work was simply chopping and measuring, he turned out to be rather good at potion-making. Snape, to say the least, was growing increasingly suspicious of his sudden abilities, but so far didn't seem to have caught on.

By way of more mundane methods of catching the Heir—or Slytherin's monster—in action, Milo had Mordy patrol the halls at night. Operating under the assumption that the monster Petrified with a gaze attack—most Petrification effects in both Milo's world and this one were gaze attacks—Mordy was the ideal choice, as the rat familiar could operate by sense of smell alone. Mordenkainen, predictably, was not happy with this particular state of affairs—less because he might run into Slytherin's monster and more because he might run into Mrs. Norris, the groundskeeper's cat.

And yet in spite of all the trouble, Scrying was failing, and there were several possible reasons for it. The two most likely, as far as Milo could tell, were that either a) the Heir's Will save was high enough that he was regularly passing his saving throws or b) there were multiple Heirs of Slytherin out there, and he wasn't providing Scrying with enough information to unambiguously define the target. Milo hadn't put any ranks in Profession (Statistician) but he could tell that it would take a lot of scrying attempts to determine beyond reasonable doubt that the spell wasn't failing because the target was making his saves. Unless he could change the odds...

"We need to find and dig up Salazar Slytherin," Milo said, as it turned out, aloud.

"Say again, mate?" Ron said in surprise. A few inconsequential NPCs turned to look briefly, then shrugged when they realized it was just Milo doing something weird again.

"No, that wouldn't work at all, nevermind. We're not trying to scry on Salazar, we're scrying on his heir..."

"Well, I'm glad that settled that," Ron said, looking somewhat bemused.

"So instead we need something of Salazar's; it should work too. By definition it's owned by his Heir now."

"Sorry mate, what who where when and why?" Ron asked.

"If we have something the target owns, it's much easier for me to find him. I don't suppose you know anything around here that belongs to Slytherin?"

"Shame we won the House Cup last year," Ron said boastfully. "Or it would have belonged to Slytherin."

"No, not the house, the founder."

"Oh. Ah, no, sorry. But if he did, you can pretty much guarantee that it'd be in his Chamber."

"Well, that's... not very helpful."

"You sure this will help us find the Heir?" Ron asked him doubtfully.

"Pretty sure, yeah," Milo said. "Or at least tell us that we need a new strategy altogether."

It didn't take them long to conclude that, in order to find something once owned by Salazar, they'd need Hermione's help, which meant going to the library. Milo put his +2 Dexterity to the test in an attempt to sneak past the librarian, Madam Pince (Milo suspected she was this universe's version of an Inevitable, although instead of punishing those who transgressed on oaths or cheated death, she came down like an avalanche on those who damaged or misplaced books). Their relations had been... frosty ever since Milo had checked out the majority of the library last year. Due to surprisingly lax rules on the matter, he'd simply taken to repeatedly renewing as-yet unread books by owl communication rather than appear in person. It was while in the library that Milo overheard whispers. Immediately, he grabbed Ron by the shoulder and pulled him behind a stack of shelves.

"Ow!" Ron said.

"Quiet!" Milo hissed. "I heard something!" Ron didn't need to be told twice, and didn't make another sound.

"Well?" someone hissed. "Did you find it?"

"Obviously not," someone else replied. "Or I would have said, 'hey, guess what, I found it, let's get out of this dive' as soon as I saw you, wouldn't I have?"

"Well then where the hell is it?"

"If I knew that—"

"It was a rhetorical question. Could you have missed it?"

"No. I tore the place apart from floor to ceiling. It wasn't there. And before you asked, yes, I used a variant of the Packing Charm to put everything back again."

"Maybe he doesn't have it? Maybe... maybe this is all a set up?"

"It's possible, but... can we really take that chance? What if he does have it?"

Milo's curiosity was beginning to get the better of him. He briefly wished he had Harry's cloak on him so he could sneak in and get a view of the whisperers, but chided himself for stupidity almost immediately, because a) he could just cast Invisibility if he wanted to, and b) he was a Wizard, dammit, not some skillmonkey scout with more recklessness than hit points. He didn't need to sneak. Not personally, anyway.

"Chain of Eyes," Milo muttered as Mordy climbed out of his Belt and dropped silently to the floor. Milo fought a brief wave of disorientation as he saw through his familiar's eyes. Chain of Eyes, which allowed the caster to see from the eyes of another creature, was an inferior Divination in most respects, but others with similar effects—such as Clairvoyance and Arcane Eye—took ten minutes to cast. A hundred rounds. Might as well be a lifetime as far as Milo was concerned.

"Did you hear something?" one of the voices asked.

"Just your incessant mouthbreathing," the other snapped.

The identity of the speakers was not what Milo was expecting (i.e., Lockhart or Snape), to say the least. He was surprised to find that the conspirators were none other than Gryffindor NPCs, Dean and Seamus.

"If he does have it," Dean said, "maybe he hid it somewhere?"

"Surely he wouldn't leave something like that out of his sight for so long," Seamus scoffed. "No-one would be so... well. Maybe he would. He is just a kid, after all."

"So, what do we do?"

"We keep looking; it's all we can do. And we'd better hope we find it. For both our sakes." With that, Seamus and Dean stood and left the library.

"Who was it?" Milo heard Ron ask, several shelves away. It was weird to see through the eyes of a different body than you heard from.

"Sean and Deamus," Milo said.

"Huh," Ron said. "Wonder what they're up to?"

"I... I have no idea," Milo said. "They're looking for something. But what? And why all the sneaking and whispering?"

"Well, mate, they're talking in a library, so whispering is sorta, you know, expected."

"Yeah... maybe." A subplot involving two completely random NPCs? And their roommates, no less. Whose stuff had they gone through? What were they looking for? Who was this 'kid' of which they spoke? Milo would have to remind Harry to add it to the Plot when he next saw him.

Hermione, as was her habit, was sitting on an overstuffed armchair near a window—although 'sitting' was perhaps a generous word for what she was doing. She was sort of half-sprawled, half-lying on the chair in an upside-down manner that only a serious lover of reading could understand.

"Oh, hey Ron, Milo," Hermione said as she saw them, turning a page of Dragons of the World, a thick tome that was lightly-charred around the edges. "What's up?"

"We were wondering if you knew where anything that belonged to Salazar Slytherin was lying?" Ron asked.

"Hmm," she asked distractedly. "Why?"

"It'll help me find his Heir," Milo said, explaining the Scrying trick.

"Not necessarily," Hermione said. "Your math is faulty. If the spell is failing because the Heir's bonus is too high, there's every chance it'll still be too high for your spell. If I understand things correctly, there won't be any way for you to tell the difference between that and it failing for another reason, like that she's protected by a Charm or there's as many Heirs of Slytherin as there are of Charlemagne."

"Yes, I know that. But it still—"

"If it's also as random as you say it is, it could never happen, regardless of the odds."

"I'm well aware—"

"I'm just making sure you've considered the possibility that this won't work and that it won't prevent you from coming up with a backup plan."

"Fair enough," Milo conceded. "Now, what do you know?"

"I'm not quite done yet."

"Gods, you're worse than the elves! If you ask them for advice, they just say both 'yes' and 'no.' You say 'yes, but first hear these important disclaimers...'"

"I prefer to think of it as 'yes, but you're asking the wrong question.' Or rather, 'you're not asking the question you think you're asking.' The last bit is that there's a chance, and I'd guess it's greater than fifty percent simply because of how wishy-washy all this 'Heir' business really is, that the legendary Heir of Slytherin, if she even exists, isn't the same as his legal Heir. We really have no idea how this works. So if you do get a belonging of Salazar's, it probably won't even help you."

"All right, all right, now will you help me?"

"Of course," Hermione said happily, sitting up straight and setting her book down. "Now, just to be certain: your magic is more about the wording of the spell than the meaning, correct?"

"Correct," Milo said, intrigued.

"Now, what exactly does the spell say that you need?"

"A possession or garment," Milo said.

"Perfect," Hermione said in a satisfied manner. "Now, I could list a variety of Slytherin's famous artifacts and you could go on a lengthy and difficult hunt for them from across the ends of the earth... but I won't do that. You already have what you need; you're standing in it."

"The library?"

She smiled. "Yes and no. Hogwarts."

"Explain."

"The three founders, after Slytherin left, wrote into their respective wills that Hogwarts would belong to 'all magical peoples of Britannia.' It's in Hogwarts: A History. So assuming the Heir is British..."

Milo blinked. He'd always considered himself something of a munchkin—it was a point of pride, in fact—but somehow all of his accomplishments paled in comparison to the scope of what Hermione was suggesting. If it worked, the precedent it would set would revolutionize Divination magic.

"Oh, and in case that doesn't work, I had another plan, too," Hermione said. "Here, look at this," she pulled the scrap of parchment she'd been using as a bookmark out of her bag as well as a quill, and quickly wrote I, Hermione Granger, do hereby affirm that I legally give the parchment bearing this writing, of which I purchased a dozen for a knut from Flourish and Blotts, to the rightful heir of Salazar Slytherin. —Hermione Granger. And then she handed it to Milo with an impious grin.

"I..." Milo didn't even know what to say. She'd just effectively rewritten the rules of a core spell twice without even pausing to think. "I just... thank you. How did you even think that up? Either of them. I mean, they're so... so..."

"Brilliant?"

"Broken."

"I guess I'll take that as a compliment," she said dubiously. "Sometimes all it takes is an outsider's perspective."

"I..."

"Best not stand around with your jaw hanging open. A bug will fly into it. I take it you two are going to Lockhart's Duelling Club? We're almost late."

o—o—o—o

"Today," Draco Malfoy said grandly, "is a very special day for the both of you."

Crabbe and Goyle stared at him expectantly. Crabbe was practically drooling. Goyle was drooling.

"You had both best prepare yourselves to witness grandeur and an acumen for machinations that befits my bent for brilliance, my inclination for inspiration, and, indeed, my propensity for perspicacity."

Crabbe frowned. "You saying you sweat a lot?"

"Shuttup Goyle, I'm on a roll," Draco snapped. He'd had to check a thesaurus out of the library to work out that 'perspicacity' bit. "Listen carefully, for I am about to finally reveal my secret plan for revenge that I've been hiding for weeks." He'd come up with a few nights before in his sleep. "We," he said, pausing dramatically, "are going to steal Milo's wand."

"Won't he just get another?" Crabbe asked.

"Yeah, boss, won't he just buy a new one?" Goyle added. Draco still hadn't managed to force them to kick that annoying habit.

"No," Draco said. "Because I haven't got to the brilliant bit, yet. We're going to steal Milo's wand... and replace it with this!" With a flourish, Draco drew a wand. "Thirteen inches of chestnut wood," he declared proudly.

"Oh," Goyle said. "That's awfully nice of you. Then he won't have to spend any money."

"Yeah, then he won't be, you know, inconvenienced." Crabbe looked at him expectantly, and Draco sighed before passing over a chocolate frog. He'd taken to encouraging their use of multi-syllabic words with sweets.

"No, it's not very nice," he said from between clenched teeth, "because this wand isn't real." He'd had to spend a lot of Father's money to get it made on such short notice.

"But I can see it," Grabbe said.

"Yeah, boss," Goyle said, giving the wand a poke. "I can touch it."

"What I mean is it's not a real wand, not that it isn't a real object. It's just a stick of wood. Watch." He pointed it at Goyle and waved it about. "Avada Kedavra."

Goyle dropped to the floor stiffly and curled up into a ball, but aside from that, nothing happened.

"See? It's harmless. Oh, get up."

It took a bit of coaxing and another chocolate frog, but eventually Goyle stopped cowering and stood up.

"The plan gets even more cunning," Draco said conspiratorially. "We'll switch their wands—right before Lockhart's Duelling Club!"

Crabbe and Goyle stared at him blankly.

"And then I'll duel him!"

They still stared at him.

"And he'll lose, because his wand is fake!"

"But boss," Crabbe said slowly. "I thought you said that wand was real?"

Malfoy considered reacting, but just sighed instead. Dealing with those two all day every day was tiring, but Father said it was good practice. He'd be dealing with incompetent fools his entire life, Father had said, so he'd best get used to it early. Few have regretted underestimating the competence of those loyal to them, he liked to say, but thousands have fallen overestimating it. He said his own father had told him the same thing. But Father always added a warning: the reverse is true for those whose loyalty is uncertain.

Lockhart's club was in an hour, which Draco largely spent doing Crabbe and Goyle's homework. Honestly, sometimes he considered just letting them fail out and be done with it, but they were useful. Sometimes. On occasion. Well, maybe one day they'd be useful, especially after Father hired them a hand-to-hand combat instructor over the summer. They were still useless at magic—maybe Lockhart's club would improve that, but Malfoy had doubts—but, hopefully, the humiliating defeat they suffered at Milo's hands last year wouldn't be repeated.

Hopefully.

Draco and a cluster of Slytherins—Blaise Zabini, Millicent Bulstrode, Pansy Parkinson—as well as a few other of the more eager students waited outside the entrance to the Great Hall. Crabbe and Goyle were doing their best to appear to be waiting casually at the nearest intersection in either direction. For his plan to succeed, he needed to be there a little in advance of his target

He waited, engaging in small talk with his classmates for a few minutes before Goyle gave him the signal (a loud fit of heavily over-acted fake coughing).

"I'd best go check on him," Draco said to the group, then hurried over to where Goyle was standing. Peering around the corner, Draco saw his mark approaching. He ducked behind the wall and waited for a few seconds, then sprung out from behind the corner, colliding directly into Milo, his second-least-favourite Gryffindor. They both tumbled to the ground in a heap.

"Malfoy!" Weasley shouted in surprise, fumbling for his wand.

"Watch where you're going!" Draco said with as much righteous anger as he could muster, climbing to his feet and brushing nonexistent dust from his robes. Peculiarly, Milo seemed to wait for Draco to step away from him before climbing to his feet, as if the act of doing so made him temporarily vulnerable.

"I always look where I'm going," Milo muttered. "It'd be damn hard to look anywhere else."

"You'll pay for this, mudblood!" Draco hissed to Milo. He wasn't actually certain of Milo's blood status, but if he wasn't muggleborn, he had very poor choice of company.

"What, are we doing this again?" Milo said. "Fine, fine, make some vaguely-defined threat or whatever. I'll even pretend to care this time."

"Ill-defined? I think not!" Draco narrowed his eyes. "I demand satisfaction! Wizard's duel."

Milo's lips quirked into a smile. "Wizard's duel, eh?" he said. "How does that work? You and me, magic only?"

"No weapons other than wands, no direct contact." Draco had seen what Milo could do with a staff.

"To the death?" Milo asked, somewhat eagerly. That kid freaked Draco out sometimes.

"No. You win either by seizing the other wizard's wand, or by incapacitating them—unconsciousness or sleep, usually."

"I accept." Milo looked like he'd just woken up to discover that it was not only his birthday, but Christmas also. Draco was looking forward to wiping that smile off his smug face. "Where and when?"

"Excellent. During Lockhart's club if he lets us... practice on each other like Quirrell."

"And if not?"

"Merlin, you ask a lot of questions. I don't know, we'll meet in the forest or something, all right? I'll send an owl."

"But what if—"

"No more questions. You accepted already. See you in the club." With that, Draco spun about on one heel and, flanked by Goyle, returned to wait outside the doors.

"Did you get it, boss?" Goyle asked.

"Yeah, did you grab it, boss?" Crabbe asked.

Draco grinned, slipping Milo's wand into his school bag. This was going to be an interesting duel...

o—o—o—o

It had taken some time—lying low slowed everything down to a crawl—but Fiona had mapped out what were, as far as she could tell, the other Fiona's (and it was another Fiona, and a dead Fiona at that) exact steps on September the Seventh. It was actually fairly simple, as it turned out, because the other her had kept detailed notes. The tricky bit was in convincing Loki that the magic had worked, and she'd completely forgotten the entire incident. At first, she'd worried about how closely they were watching her, but then she'd thought about it, and really... not that closely, when it came down to it. They clearly hadn't noticed the other Fiona making her audio recording, just as they hadn't noticed her digital records on the Machine, or they would have destroyed those. Well, they'd certainly tried with the Machine, so maybe she couldn't be too certain about that.

More to the point, they hadn't even tried to destroy her cassette, meaning they weren't watching her home (at one point in the recording, Sprocket's plaintive cries for food were audible, so the recording must have been done in her flat). It was possible they were watching the station, however, as that had been where they'd got the first Fiona. Well, what she hoped was the first Fiona; she had no idea how many iterations of this crime there had been.

If they weren't watching her home, their surveillance was sloppy. She was either dealing with an amateur or someone who simply deigned her beneath their notice. She was leaning towards the second option, simply because she'd never remembered underestimating the enigmatic Loki.

It was clear what the other Fiona must have done, because the other Fiona had the same lead she had: a name.

Dursley.

She itched to tug at that lead like a mosquito bite, but she knew she couldn't. Not yet. Doing that was what ended the other Fiona. This whole situation getting beyond her—she had only limited experience with conducting a full-blown investigation. She was only a sergeant, what could she do by herself? She needed allies, she needed resources, she needed a warrant—but she knew that nobody would believe her story.

And that was why Fiona, for the first time in her life, committed a premeditated criminal act. With no known means of contacting Loki directly, she was forced to rely on something rather more blunt.

She gave the spray can three shakes with one hand, held up the stencil she'd cut out ahead of time with her other, and with the press of a button defaced the pristine white picket fence.

Inspector Hannigan Surrey PD knows about the magic.

And just like that, her trap was set.

o—o—o—o—o—o

Author's Notes: Turns out having my Teeth of Wisdom +2 out was much less conducive to writing than I'd imagined. Sorry for the delay, but in return, I present my favourite chapter title so far. Alternate titles: I Scry With My Arcane Eye, Scry Versus Scry, Scry Versus Spy, For Scrying Out Loud, Scry Kids. (I apologize for nothing. If you really hated puns, you never would have made it through an entire book of something I wrote).

Chapter 10: The Duel

Today's Character Sheet: ?sheetid=628437

I'm keeping track of Milo's XP offline because it often changes several times a chapter and would be a hassle to update the character sheet that frequently.

With most of the students of Hogwarts (especially those of Gryffindor and Slytherin houses) assembled in the Great Hall, Lockhart was clearly in his element. Mordy, sitting on Milo's shoulder, was frantically transcribing everything the flamboyant Defence Professor said for future reference. The rat drew a few strange looks from some of the older students who were less familiar with Milo's Familiar, especially the Muggleborns. While most of those raised by wizards hadn't seen a rat writing by dipping its paws into an inkwell, they'd seen enough peculiarity in their lives to take such things in stride.

"...and, after defeating—or charming, as the case may be—his cronies, I duelled him and his giants into submission, thus freeing the townsfolk from their terrible curse. You can read all about it in Gilderoy Lockhart and the Night of the Octopus, an upcoming novella by Angelita Shaw. Be warned that her account is somewhat fictionalized—Angelita, unfortunately, was forced by her editors to tone down some of the action to make the story sound more believable. Alas, but the truth is often stranger than fiction. You can always drop by my office if you want the real story, of course. Where was I? Ah, yes—duelling. As I'm sure you can tell by now, duelling is an important skill that is often sadly neglected in this modern world. "

Milo was aware that wanded wizards followed a different mechanic for increasing in level than he did, but if it was even remotely similar, Lockhart must be one of the most powerful wizards alive. The sheer number of encounters he'd won boggled the mind.

The crowd around Milo jostled a bit as someone tried to duck and weave through the throng of students. Milo turned to see Harry, covered almost head-to-toe in mud and soaked through, push his way between a pair of third-year Ravenclaws.

"Sorry I'm late," he said to Milo, Ron, and Hermione, gasping for breath.

"What happened, mate?" Ron asked.

"Wood got me out of bed early for surprise Quidditch practice," Harry said miserably. "It was dreadful."

"But look at the weather!" Hermione gestured to the Great Hall ceiling. Ominous dark grey clouds hid the sky, pouring rain as if Obad-Hai himself had cast Create Water.

"My point precisely," Harry said sourly.

"Prestidigitation," Milo muttered, and, one cubic foot at a time, Harry's robes cleaned themselves.

"Thanks. What'd I miss?" Harry asked.

"Lockhart bragging about his past accomplishments," Ron said. "Some of which might even have happened. Also, Malfoy challenged Milo here to a duel."

"Pft," Harry said contemptuously. "That should be fun to watch. Just make sure to leave enough of him for the rest of us to have our turn."

"No promises," Milo grinned.

o—o—o—o

Fiona paced outside the inspector's office somewhat nervously. This conversation had to be handled carefully, which was hardly her forte. She'd been waiting there for fifteen minutes for Hannigan to return from a meeting of some variety. Maybe I should wait until tomorrow, she thought to herself. Or come back with something more substantial. Yeah. I'll just walk back to my desk as if I was never—

"PS Smythe?" It was Inspector Hannigan.

"Shit," Fiona muttered.

"Excuse me, Sergeant?"

"Shit, sir!" Fiona replied snappily, breaking into a panic. "I mean, wait," Oh my god, I just swore in front of the inspector. "Dammit!" Shit! I did it again! What the hell was I thinking?

"Do you... perhaps need a moment?" Hannigan asked curiously.

"Ah... um. No. Can I talk to you?"

"Well, I rather think that's what we're already doing, sergeant. I gather from your... well, from you, that what you mean is, can you talk to me in my office? In which case, the answer is yes, but I've only got five minutes before a meeting with the Force Improvement Team."

Fiona nodded, not quite trusting her mouth. Honestly, swearing because you swore... pull yourself together.

"Um. Perhaps you'd best sit down," she suggested.

Hannigan shrugged. "I'll only be here a moment, I might as well stand; the wife says it's good for the back."

Fiona took a deep breath. Best get this over with as fast as possible. Like ripping off a bandage. "Inspector, there's no easy way to say this, but you've had your memory altered by magic."

Hannigan stared at her blankly for a second, looking for all the world like an English student trying to parse 'Jabberwocky' for the first time.

"Look, as I told you, I'm quite busy," he said irritably. "So if you don't have anything important to say, I suggest you go on your way and we forget about this little joke. Some office prank or dare, I presume? No matter."

"I'm dead serious, inspector."

"Magic," the inspector said flatly.

"Yes, sir. Magic."

"You mean PCP?"

"No, sir. I mean sorcery. Enchantments. Witchcraft. Like in the books."

"You're putting me on." It was not a question.

"No, sir." Fiona pulled her tape recorder from her pocket and placed it on the desk.

"I don't suppose you have any proof of this ... this... well, whatever this is!"

Fiona pressed play.

"Excuse me, sir," she heard her own voice say. "Could you do me a quick favour?"

"Well, I suppose, sergeant. What can I do for you?" It was the inspector.

"If you don't mind, I'm going to press record, here, and then say a bunch of stuff that you're not really going to understand, and all I want is for you to listen and then confirm at the end that you heard it."

The inspector stared at Fiona peculiarly, then looked down at the tape, an unspoken question on his lips. Instead of saying anything, however, he just listened to the recording.

"What's this for?"

"A surprise. You'll see, sir."

"I'm not going to regret this, am I?"
There was a short period of silence.

"No-one can know the future, sir."

"Hmph. Very well, get on with it."

"Magic is real, sir, near as I can tell. Someone's been using it to alter the memory of the police in this station to forget as soon as we discover it, and someone used it to assault me and my partner, PC Evan Travis, at Number 4, Privet Drive in Little Whinging on July 31st, and then to facilitate a jailbreak from this station. During this event, the display on the Machine was destroyed, and the memories of several officers, ourselves included, was replaced with a fictitious series of events. Allegedly, a junkie that was brought to the station got loose and smashed up some property before being detained and transferred. However, I've checked, and there's no proper documentation for any of this."

"What, really? I'll be having a word with some people over that. Oh, right, sorry, I'm not to interrupt."

"No, that's quite all right; I'm about done anyway. There's more, but I can tell you after. So, sir, can you please confirm what you heard?"

"A fascinating tale about magic and memory modification and such."

"And what is the date today?"

"Ah—the eighteenth of September, I believe."

"And would you agree that, theoretically speaking, if tomorrow you hear this recording and don't remember it, that you'll accept what I said as true?"

Inspector Hannigan looked up at Fiona, a strange look on his face.

"Well, yes, I suppose that would follow. Unless I'm sloshed, of course. Now, what was all this about?"

"Surprise, sir."

Fiona stopped the recording.

"Well." The inspector sat down heavily on his old, worn leather chair with a slightly dazed expression. "That's that, then."

"Sir? Believe me, I know it can be a lot—"

"The chair's seen something new. So. Magic?"

"Magic, sir."

"Shit."

"Yes, sir."

"Tell me everything, sergeant. Start from the beginning."

"Your meeting, sir?"

"Bugger the meeting."

So she told him everything, starting from the beginning.

o—o—o—o

It wasn't long before Lockhart had them all pair off and try to disarm each other, much as Quirrell—well, Voldemort, really—had. Unlike He-Who-Must-Not-Be-Named, Lockhart apparently hadn't felt that padded mats were a necessary precaution. Harry wound up with Hermione, Ron with Neville, Hannah with Lavender, and Milo, of course, with Draco.

"Afraid yet, freak?" Draco sneered at him.

"Oh, wake up, Malfoy," Milo shrugged. "My rat Mordenkainen could duel you one-handed."

Draco did a double-take. "Your rat—who?"

"Mordenkainen," Milo said. "My rat." He gestured to the back of the room, where Milo's Familiar was lurking, waiting to take notes on various Slytherins' fighting styles and generally level of competency. Milo raised his left hand. "One-handed."

"Agh! Never mind! Draw your wand, freak, and prepare to see what a pureblooded wizard is capable of!"

"What, like your dad and his friends?" Milo said dismissively, drawing his wand. "Eh."

Malfoy snapped. "You'll pay for your insolence!" he shouted, his face mottled with fury. "Everte Statum!"

Milo was lifted off his feet and thrown bodily against the wall behind him. "Feather Fall!" he cast, surprised, and slowed to the ground. "Grease!" Milo targeted the area that Draco was standing on.

Draco almost lost his balance, but reacted quickly. "What! How? Colloshoo," he cast at his own feet, sticking him to the ground. "Expelliarmus!"

"Greater Mirror Image." Four identical Milo's appeared around him, all still floating in the air as Milo descended. One was hit by Expelliarmus, and burst into tiny fragments of magic. Milo wasn't worred—the images from the improved version of the spell regenerated in time. He was certain he could end this duel any moment he wanted to, but decided to take advantage of his school-sanctioned chance to get a couple of free hits off on Draco. "Glitterdust." The area around Draco exploded into thousands of tiny motes of brilliant golden light.

"Scourgify," Draco cast, and the area around his eyes cleared up, allowing him to see. Milo was surprised—nobody else he'd used Glitterdust on had thought of that. On the other hand, Draco might be one of the only wanded wizards he'd fought who had seen him fight before... "Oppugno!" Draco shouted. The Glitterdust flew off of him and directly at Milo, with a menace. Come on, Will save, don't fail me now... Milo had a +8 bonus and the DC was 18, so he had around a 55% chance to succeed. Anything over ten would do...

Four. Crap.

"Gah!" Milo said, the light blinding him. "Who fails a save against their own spell? Mordy!" Milo's familiar scrambled from his position and onto Milo's shoulder. "Chain of Eyes." Milo couldn't believe he'd actually cast that spell twice now—most Wizards lived and died (or achieved godhood) without even learning it. It was approaching time to finish this charade. He'd have to investigate more efficient means of fighting while blind, preferably ones that didn't require a second-level spell slot and an action in combat.

Through Mordenkainen's eyes, Milo saw Draco grin, and realized what had happened: by commanding his familiar to come to him, Milo had given away which of his identical clones—there were five, now—was really him.

"Serpensortia," Draco whispered. A long, night-black snake shot out of his wand and shot towards Milo. He briefly considered using Tongues to mimic a Parselmouth's ability, but dismissed the idea. The last thing he wanted was people to think that he was the Heir of Slytherin. As the snake approached, Milo drew his darkwood eleven-foot pole, wielding it in both hands as an improvised reach weapon while simultaneously readying a spell. The snake leapt through the air, and, as it entered within Milo's reach, provoked an attack of opportunity. Rather than attempt to strike the snake, which wouldn't have a hope of success with the mountain of penalties Milo would incur, he used Evasive Reflexes to sidestep away from the snake. Milo let the pole fall to the ground, and called his Elven thinblade to hand just as the snake soared past him and through his now-threatened area. Milo's pirouetted, sword flashing.

There were two meaty thuds behind him before the now-dead magical snake vanished, the magic holding it together gone.

Milo spun, towards Draco, releasing his readied spell. "Evard's Black Tentacles."

Hundreds of black tentacles burst from the floor around Draco, grabbing his arms and pulling him awkwardly—his feet were still glued to the floor—to the ground.

"Mordy," Milo nodded, sheathing his sword in his Belt of Hidden Pouches. The familiar scurried from Milo's shoulder towards the struggling Draco and, with a casual flick of its paw, grabbed the Slytherin boy's wand before doing a little bow. Milo dismissed the tentacles and Grease.

"You—you cheated!" Draco shouted, climbing to his feet. "And give me that back!" Mordy shrugged, dropped the wand, and returned to Milo.

"Cheated?" Milo asked, thinking back over the rules. "Huh. I guess I did." He'd forgotten that no other weapons than wands were allowed.

It was then that Milo realized they had an audience.

The rest of the Club had, at some point, abandoned any pretense of practicing on each other in favour of watching their battle.

Ah, crap. There was no way he was going to walk away from this without some ridiculous detention. Milo wondered if he should start researching a means of getting Simulacrum early so he could send an identical copy of himself to do punishments for him. That would also get him out of McGonagall's ridiculous remedial Transfigurations.

"Well, I daresay," Lockhart said, breaking the silence. "I've never seen a duel quite like that—that didn't include me in it, of course. A remarkable show from both of you. Five points for Slytherin, ten points for Hufflepuff!" Lockhart hesitated for a second. "I did say 'disarm-only,' however, so if anyone tries something like that again, I'll have to take rather sterner measures."

"But—but I'm in Gryffindor!" Milo protested, but nobody heard him over the sudden thunderous applause. They should have identifying markings on our robes, Milo thought. Colour-coordinated trim or badges or something.

As the applause died down, Milo heard some bitter muttering from the Slytherin section, though he didn't catch who was speaking.

"...probably showing off for Lockhart..."

"...they say he scored perfect on that ridiculous quiz..."

"...they also say he Petrified Peeves..."

Any attempt at eavesdropping was cut off by a crowd of students from his own house.

"Spectacular!" Fred Weasley said.

"Brilliant!" added his twin.

"The expression on Malfoy's face when you used those tentacle thingies—perfect!" Ron said, a dreamy expression on his face. "I just wish someone had taken a photograph..."

"I thought he almost had you with the snake," Harry said. "I was this close to..." he lowered his voice, "you know, to telling it to stop, but... with all the people around... well, I thought you could probably handle it."

"I just thought I should say that was extremely dangerous and I'm amazed nobody was hurt—Draco could have thrown you clear out the window—and that I strongly disapprove, but..." Hermione's face cracked into a smile. "Congratulations nevertheless. He had that coming, the git."

"That thing with the sword—that was so cool!" Hannah said. "How did you do that?"

"Magic," Milo grinned. "I've got a pin enchanted with a spell—Mirror Move—that lets me learn how to do pretty much anything that I see someone else do, and a spell—Heroics—that lets me temporarily teach someone else how to do things, so I just grabbed Ron over the summer, pumped him full of magic and—" but nobody was really listening to him; they were too busy excitedly recounting the details of the duel.

"I thought he had you when he used your glittered dust against you," he heard Neville say. "Showed him. Killed the snake blind... amazing. Just bloody amazing."

"Shame Dean and Seamus weren't here," Harry said. "They'd have loved that."

"Yeah..." Milo frowned, looking around—Glitterdust had worn off, but he was still using Mordy's vision to get a little extra height (his familiar had moved to the top of his head) to see over the other students. Probably sixty-to-seventy percent of Hogwarts' students were at the club. That left most of the school completely unwatched... "Mordy," Milo muttered in their secret language. "Go check on Seamus and Dean, would you?"

"Sometimes I feel like I do everything around here," the rat muttered, climbing down Milo's robes and scurrying out of the hall.

"Right, calm down, everybody," Lockhart said, his voice magically augmented to carry over the crowd. "Pick your partners, and let's try it again. Try to stick to Expelliarmus this time..."

Milo, already critically short on spells, decided to sit this one out. Besides, he'd already earned more XP than his weekly loss from item crafting. Instead, he picked a place on the sidelines and watched the fights progress.

He barely noticed the first instance—he'd been watching Hannah's match with Lavender—and dismissed the second as chance, but by the third time, it was clear. Neville was improving, fast. Out of five rounds, Ron had only managed to disarm him once. Milo recalled in Quirrell's class that Neville had seemed to have a hard time learning the Disarming Charm, but now that he had it... well. Milo was hardly an expert in the local magic, but his latest theory was that it was skill-based. In order to cast a spell, a skill check had to be made with a DC based on the complexity of the spell. Neville was making that check almost every time. He wasn't the fastest at it, and he wasn't the most confident, but he did seem to be having more reliable success than most other students, save for those of higher years.

The other surprising battle was between Harry and Hermione. The surprise was that Harry was winning. Hermione was a bookworm with near-eidetic memory in a world where knowledge was quite literally power, and Milo would have bet money on her against any wizard or witch of the same level. Harry, it seemed, had been practicing this spell in particular—though Milo hadn't ever seen him do it. As for the others, while they didn't stand out in quite the same way that Harry and Neville were, they'd clearly advanced at a rate that simply dwarfed their abilities even at the end of last term. Still nothing like what the sixth-and-seventh-years at the far side of the Great Hall were doing, but nevertheless impressive.

Milo wondered if he could try to help Harry and the others progress at an even faster rate. The only thing better than a highly-optimized character was a party of highly-optimized characters.

Milo's chain of thought was broken by an empathic sending by Mordy. Success, alarm, surprise. Using the still-active Chain of Eyes to switch back to his familiar's vision, he saw the familiar sight of the second-year dormitory in Gryffindor Tower—though from the peculiar view of a rat only a few inches tall. Irritatingly, he couldn't hear anything (the spell was called Chain of Eyes, not Chain of Ears) but he could see just fine.

Dean and Seamus were going through his stuff, as well as Harry's, Neville's, and Ron's. Not that he actually had any stuff, of course; he kept everything he owned in his Belt of Hidden Pouches (except for his Dedicated Wright, Cog, and his mountain of salt, but those were at the Burrow) by using owl post to send partially completed items back and forth, Milo could provide the necessary spells and XP while Cog provided the time and effort. Upon finding all of Milo's drawers, as well as the space under and even over his four-poster bed, they moved onto the other occupants of the dorm.

So... they were talking about me in the library? But what could I possibly have that they want?

Milo heard a commotion, and flicked his vision back to his own eyes. The Club was over, and people were filing out of the Great Hall's doors. His party members were waiting around him.

"Coming, Milo?" Hermione asked him.

"Hmm? Right, yeah." He got to his feet.

"Whoa, what?" Harry said suddenly, reaching for his wand.

"Ah... what's up, Harry?" Ron asked cautiously.

"The voice!" Harry said.

"What... what voice?"

"You—you didn't hear it?"

"Um. Nope."

"Hang on," Milo said. "What did it say?"

"Um," Harry said nervously. "Something weird. About ripping, tearing, and killing. Ah. Me, specifically."

"Are you certain?" Hermione asked Harry, who nodded. "Did you, you know hear it—with your ears, that is? Or, in your head?"

"Not sure I'd know the difference," Harry said. "I don't exactly hear voices in my head regularly."

"Lesser Telepathic Bond," Milo cast. It would sound like this, he thought towards Harry.

"Whoa. Nope. Not like that."

"Not like what?" Hermione asked.

"The, ah, voice I just heard... in my head..." Harry explained unhelpfully. Ron and Hermione stared at him blankly. "Look, Milo did it."

"Ah," they said together, as if that explained everything.

"So could it be something invisible, do you think?" Hermione asked.

"Detect Invisibility," Milo cast, scanning around. "I don't see anything invisible, but that doesn't count for much in these parts."

"Maybe it was some kinda prank," Ron suggested. "Like a trick from Malfoy, to freak you out."

"Possible," Hermione said. "I can think of loads of ways to do it with pretty common spells. Still, if it happens again, we should tell a teacher."

"I dunno, Hermione," Ron said. "Hearing voices isn't usually seen as a good sign, even in the wizarding world. I'm not saying you're crazy, mate, but, well, it could look that way to people. Best keep it between us."

Milo switched his vision back to Mordy's, but Dean and Seamus were gone. The room was pristine once more—as with their earlier conversation, they must have used the Packing Charm to put things back where they were. Was his room the same as the one that Dean had already searched? Why would they come back? Perhaps Seamus hadn't trusted the job Dean had done? Milo needed more information.

o—o—o—o

Draco sat down in an emerald-green armchair in the Slytherin Common Room, looking at Milo's wand.

"Lumos," he muttered. The wand tip glowed feebly and sputtered out a few seconds later. "Impossible," he muttered. This wand was real—it resisted working for him, but there was no doubt that this was a wizard's wand. And yet, the freak had managed to use magic anyway.

Had Milo used another wand in the duel? It wasn't impossible that he had a spare, although Ollivander charged a small fortune for a copy wand. Apparently, it was much more difficult to make a wand identical to a previous wand rather than simply create them all differently. But Draco had seen Milo draw his wand from the same pocket that Draco had put the fake one into, and there had been only one there. So how...?

Could it be that... no, that would be impossible. Unless...

Draco frowned.

"Crabbe! Goyle!" he shouted, and the two came rushing out of their dorm.

"What do you need, boss?" Crabbe asked.

"Yeah boss, what do you find equineccessary, boss?" Goyle asked, holding out his hand.

"That word doesn't mean what you think it does," Draco muttered idly. "So no chocolate for you." He looked up at the two of them. "Milo could use magic in that duel," he said quietly, "so he had to have had a proper wand. That means that he must have switched wands with me before I switched them with him, then switched back during the duel. He probably had that weird rat of his do it."

"But... what?" Crabbe asked. Clearly it had gone beyond him.

Goyle scratched his head. "Had to have... had..." he said to himself, slowly.

"What I'm saying is he must have known what my plan was!" Draco shouted. "So—" he froze, suddenly. So one of them must have told him. But neither Crabbe nor Goyle would have done so, so...

Maybe...

At least one of them wasn't Crabbe or Goyle—and were therefore the last people he should be voicing his suspicions to.

"Agh!" Draco shouted dramatically. "He's outsmarted me again!"

Of course, he hadn't been outsmarted; nobody outsmarts Draco Malfoy. But they seemed convinced, and made feeble attempts at consoling him.

So... Polyjuice? Draco thought. What was it they'd learned in Herbology? Mandrake root restored people who had been Transfigured. Fortunately, he knew just where to get some.

o—o—o—o

"Did they say anything?" Milo asked Mordy in the Common Room. He wasn't afraid of being overheard; their secret language was, by definition, uncrackable.

"Not much," the familiar replied. "Just a lot of swearing and blaming each other for failure."

"Odd," Milo said. "I've never really paid them much attention, but Dean and Seamus seemed like pretty good friends."

"About that," Mordy said. "I wasn't sure before, but now I am. That wasn't Dean and Seamus."

"What?" Milo asked. "How could you tell?"

"By the smell. They smell... different. Not completely different, but somewhat different. A bit like... like two people mixed into one. In Seamus's case, I think one of those people is female."

"How come you didn't notice this earlier? We sleep in the same room as them!"

"You and I have the same skills, and Scent is Survival-based! What Wizard has ever put ranks in Survival?"

"Ah... fair point," Milo conceded. "I forgot about that."

"Of course you did. Who reads the Scent rules? Not Wizards, that's for sure."

"I'll make you teensy little goggles or something that boost Survival. They'll be adorable."

Mordy's eyes narrowed.

"I mean badass. They'll be badass. Easy words to mistake."

"You do realize that, seeing as how we're empathically bonded, it's completely impossible for you to lie to me, don't you?"

"Yes—which is why I wouldn't possibly have tried to lie. And if anything makes you think otherwise, you must be mistaken."

Mordy just shook his head. "So what do you think it is? Possession? The Imperius curse?"

"I'm not sure," Milo said. "But we have ways of finding out."

o—o—o—o—o—o

Roleplaying Tip: This one's more roleplay-y than 'over-the-top munchkinry' like many of my D&D Tips, but I've found that nothing helps you get into character and stay there like drawing your character. Once, someone playing an illiterate barbarian in my party drew all of his items on his character sheet, rather than writing them. You don't have to go that far, however. Even if you don't have any artistic talent at all, you can use something like Heromachine (a web app designed for creating superheroes, but works for D&D—and other rpgs—too) to do the work for you. Having an illustration of your character somewhere on your character sheet helps remind you that your character is an independent entity with a personality and goals that may not be the same as your 'meta-goals' (become the best wizard ever, get sweet magic loot, etc.). Ideally, these should not be in conflict with each other (a holy paladin on a crusade for justice and goodness wouldn't be doing his job right if he didn't seize every opportunity to be more effective at what he does), but it's nice to be reminded that they're separate, and that your character might want things in addition to what is strictly pragmatic. Optimization is a blast, roleplaying is a blast, but the best by far is when you do both simultaneously. There's a weird idea that they're mutually exclusive, which I think is untrue. Some people might prioritize one or the other, or be naturally inclined one way or the other, but that's separate from being unable to do them both.

Wow, that devolved into a tangent quickly. Sorry about that—but I think I'll let it stand. In return, I'll give a more typical tip as well. This one doesn't devolve into theoretical optimization, so you can actually use it around the table.

D&D Tip: You can make attacks with more than just your two hands, for example, an unarmed strike can be with any part of the body. Similarly, armour spike attacks, which don't require their own feat to be effective, can be delivered via a spiky knee to the stomach or a body slam. Why does this matter? Because it leaves your hands free. There are many reasons one would need their hands for something else—for example, when using a ranged weapon. If you're a ranged combatant in a class with martial weapon proficiency, such as a Ranger, you can still threaten squares, flank, and make attacks of opportunity with armour spikes and other unconventional weapons (Complete Scoundrel adds some weapons like boot daggers, but they have a -2 to attack, so I recommend armour spikes). Even if you have a terrible strength score, I recommend such a weapon strongly, if only for the flanking benefits you can provide your teammates. Even if you never intend to fight in melee, at some point, someone will try to fight you. Your rogue will thank you, at the very least.

For some kinds of melee fighters, armour spikes are even more important. For example, say you use a reach weapon like a Glaive. These come with the downside of not being able to attack, or threaten, enemies adjacent to you, which can be a serious problem. However, with armour spikes, you never have to drop your polearm and switch to a backup weapon—the backup weapon is built in, and you can't be disarmed of it. This allows you to threaten a much larger area, making you more effective overall at whatever you do.

In addition to weapons with reach, armour spikes (and unarmed strike, etc.) are awesome for two-weapon fighting. Both your hands are free, so you can dual wield a one-handed weapon and the spikes and still leave room for a shield, or, for ludicrous damage, you can use a weapon like a greatsword in both hands with 1.5x strength and still make off-hand attacks with armour spikes (with only .5x strength added). Note that it's generally better to use Power Attack with a two-handed weapon than to two-weapon fight, but if you're a class that gets a lot of bonus damage (like a swordsage or sneak attacker) then this is the combo for you.

Note: Pathfinder developers recently ruled in a FAQ that you can't do this, but it still works just fine in D&D.

Chapter 11: Trick or Treat

SKITTERskitterskitter—SKITTERskitterskitter.

Hannah awoke with a jolt. She was sitting in the Common Room, having fallen asleep doing History of Magic homework. What the heck was that sound?

SKITTERskitterskitter. It sounded a bit like rain, only heavier and more infrequent—and it was coming from inside the room.

Suspicions growing, Hannah reached for her wand. The fires had long since been reduced to simple glowing embers, but the room was somewhat lit by moonlight streaking through the tall, wide arched windows. She thought she could see movement at the foot of the staircase near the boy's dormitories.

SKITTERskitterskitterSKITTERSKITTERSKITTER—

Hannah threw herself from her armchair just before a monster from nightmares (was this a nightmare?) leapt at her, knocking the chair over. A long, thin something almost thirty feet long collided with the red-and-gold armchair like a freight train. She could barely make it out in the darkness, save for occasional glimpses of reflected moonlight.

"St-stube-stupa-Stupefy!" A red bolt flew out of her wand as she sent a Stunner, which collided with the creature dead-on. They'd just learned them in the Duelling Club; the advanced spell was almost beyond her. The beast skittered around awkwardly as its extremities slowly realized their brain was on a lunch break before coming, finally, to a stop. "Lumos." Her glowing wand tip revealed a black-and-red centipede comparable in length to a carriage of the Hogwarts Express with sharp mandibles (or fangs? pincers? Hannah wasn't sure which term applied) to match. They were at least as long as her forearm, and were wickedly serrated. Just as suddenly as it appeared, it promptly vanished.

Hannah sighed, catching her breath, and collapsed back into her seat. A few seconds later, she stood up, and shouted.

"Milo!"

"Well done!" Milo said, suddenly appearing in the middle of the room. "I must admit, I had my doubts when you immediately went for the most powerful spell you knew—clever application of something more reliably cast is often more prudent—but then you pulled it off anyway and your aim was perfect. Awesome."

"What the heck was that thing?" Hannah asked, anger slowly rising.

"A huge monstrous centipede from Hell," Milo shrugged. "Or someplace like it."

"Look—I know I said I was on board with your whole 'training' thing, but the way you described it sounded more like, I don't know, Quidditch practice or studying. You summon a monster and we hit it with spells. I was most decidedly not expecting to spend the next four weeks on my toes against surprise sabre-toothed demon weasels, hippogriffs, gorillas, bats the size of horses, packs of Abyssal octopi in the lake, and humongous monstrous centipedes from Hell! Especially humongous monstrous centipedes from Hell!"

"Real Abyssal octopi hunt in packs of hundreds," Milo said. "Not trios."

"That's your objection—argh! No, okay. Calm. I am calm," Hannah said. "I agreed because I wanted to be more useful in an emergency. I didn't sign on for a life of surprise and paranoia."

"Well, if you were expecting the surprise, it wouldn't be much of a surprise at all, would it?"

"That's exactly my point. I could have had a heart attack, and that's assuming the giant rats didn't eat me alive."

"You were never in any real danger; my summoned monsters were ordered to remain non-lethal. And in the huge monstrous centipede from Hell's case, not to use his venom."

"But why can't the others and I learn to fight in a more controlled environment? Like in the Duelling Club."

"Because if Slytherin's monster—or something sent by You-Know-Who—attacks you, it won't be in a controlled environment," Milo said seriously. "It'll be a surprise attack, and it'll be when you least expect it. And you won't even know what it'll look like when it happens. From what I can tell, and I know it sounds insane, people here actually learn how to do things by doing exactly that thing. I mean, look at the courses. You actually learn how to make potions in Potions class, rather than by killing orcs and giant spiders and saving children and the like. So I'm teaching you how to fight against surprise monsters."

"That... fine, that actually makes sense," Hannah admitted reluctantly. "But you should still ask for permission first. It's the polite thing to do."

"Hmm. Good idea; I wonder why I didn't think of that," Milo said without a trace of irony. "If only so Ron stops glaring at me from across the table. He should learn not to take a few giant bees in his bed quite so personally. Do I have your permission to train you to protect yourself against surprise attacks by launching surprise attacks against you on occasion?" Milo asked.

"Not when I'm sleeping or I'll never close my eyes again—and no more Hellipedes."

"Deal."

Hannah hesitated for a second. "And I think you're wrong," she said. "I think we learn in much the same way. I think you're confusing gaining knowledge and gaining power. People tend not to learn much by killing."

Milo gave her a perplexed look. "But knowledge is power."

"Is it, though?" Hannah asked. "There's more to growing up than getting bigger." She stifled a yawn. "Just something to think about. I'm going to bed."

She climbed the stairs to the girls' dormitories, leaving Milo looking troubled in the Common Room.

o—o—o—o

Draco held the writhing, shrieking mandrake root down with one gloved hand, a cleaver held high in the other.

"Why do they have to look so human?" he muttered to himself. The words fell silently on his muffled ears. He'd been standing for several minutes in the outskirts of the Forbidden Forest in the dead of night.

He supposed it wasn't too late to back out now. He could sneak back into the greenhouse and return the freakish plant—or, for that matter, just toss it in the forest. Plants like forest, right? It would be happy there... he cut off that line of thought before it could go too far. Best not to attribute human emotions and desires to a root.

But it looks so alive...

Father wouldn't be too weak to chop up a plant, he thought to himself coldly. Father would destroy whatever or whoever stood in his way, if it benefitted him.

Besides, they're going to be used for potions, anyway.

Draco led out a deep breath and swallowed, feeling a renewed sense of determination.

With a flash of reflected starlight, the cleaver came down hard, and the shrieking stopped.

o—o—o—o

Snape finished sealing the hardened glass flask for owl transport. The last thing anyone wanted was a month's worth of Polyjuice potion raining from the sky because of a poorly sealed or cracked container.

Once more, he wondered what Lucius could possibly want with so much of the potion. He'd already had to send all that he kept on hand to the elder Malfoy, as Polyjuice took a lunar cycle to brew. Of course, there were thousands of potential uses someone like Lucius, who had his fingers in more pies than you could count, could devise with Polyjuice. Blackmail, spying, and theft, to name a few. And if that was all he was doing, it was none of Snape's business. He frankly didn't care one way or the other if Lucius was committing what were, on the whole, conventional crimes to gain conventional wealth and conventional power.

But if there was something else afoot... well. Lucius Malfoy was rarely a predictable man, but there was one clear and obvious candidate for replacement. Somebody that few knew personally, somebody in a trusted position, somebody few would miss. Everything pointed at one person. In fact, it was practically proverbial: "when in doubt, suspect the Defence Professor."

Snape tied the flask to the legs of the owl and sent it on its way.

The amount of damage one man, whom everybody suspected and who had no allies, could do was limited, even with a disguise as perfect as one created by one of Snape's potions. So Snape would watch Gilderoy Lockhart.

o—o—o—o

"Free sweets!" Draco said, smiling, to a cluster of first-year Hufflepuffs. They turned to look at him, and his tray of handmade sweets, for a long, tense moment.

Then they screamed and fled.

Draco sighed. This was going to be more difficult than he'd anticipated. He'd already tried dosing all the Slytherins in the Common Room with his mandrake-laced treats, but he hadn't made any discoveries except that Marcus Flint had been transfiguring his face to hide his acne.

Hallowe'en was only a few days away. He'd hoped to get to the bottom of the Polyjuice mystery before then, so that he could utilize Crabbe and Goyle in some sort of as-yet unknown Hallowe'en-themed revenge plot against his nemeses in Gryffindor. While it was true that both Crabbe and Goyle had been unaffected by the mandrake root—he'd given it to them disguised as sweets to reward them for expanding their vocabulary—he'd hoped to catch the culprit disguised as them once more. Since he didn't know much beyond the fact that somebody had (probably) used Polyjuice to spy on him, there was no way to know how pervasive the use of the potion was among his enemies.

He'd come to what was, of course, the only reasonable conclusion: that he should secretly drug the student body at random for a prolonged period of time. At some point, one of them was bound to take the bait while in disguise. It was the week leading up to Hallowe'en, so it wasn't as peculiar to be handing out sweets as it might otherwise have been. Unfortunately, students at Hogwarts seemed to have some sort of (completely unfounded) superstition against accepting free food from a member of Slytherin house.

He'd have to alter his plan somewhat if he was to succeed.

o—o—o—o

"Explosive Runes," Milo cast, scratching a curious-looking symbol into the hard bronze of a knut with a chisel before throwing it onto the small pile of similarly-marked coins. "That should do. Mordy?" The tiny rat scurried up the table leg in the dusty abandoned classroom and started slipping knuts into a bandolier he wore across his chest, eyes firmly shut. "Careful with those," Milo said seriously.

"Don't worry so much, boss," Mordy said. "As long as I don't try and read them, we don't have anything to worry about." That much was true—the runes were carved in their secret language, and Milo was immune to his own traps, so theoretically only Mordy could trigger them. Still, it made Milo nervous to carry that volume of arcane high explosive on his person.

But Hallowe'en was tomorrow, and he had to be prepared. Last year a Troll nearly killed him and his friends; what would happen this year? Between his surprise summoned attacks and Lockhart's club, his party members had significantly increased in power since last year—and so had he, for that matter. It stood both to reason and convention that their challenges would scale accordingly.

As Milo tried to predict what would be thrown at him tomorrow, Mordy pulled a pair of tiny, finely-wrought brass-and-crystal goggles over his eyes and tied thin silk bracers around each wrist. In all, the familiar struck a comical image, but it would be a fool who underestimated him—and in all likelihood, a dead fool at that, for these seemingly-innocent items wielded great power. Or, perhaps more precisely, they wielded minor power in a uniquely lethal manner.

o—o—o—o

"I give up," said a boy who looked very much like Dean Thomas in a dark, largely-empty hallway on Hallowe'en morning. "We've been here for a month and we haven't found anything. This is a school; there are hundreds of old black leather diaries floating around. I want to go home."

"We can't give up now; we're just starting to make progress," said someone who looked very much like Seamus Finnigan. "We just need to widen the search. What if he gave it to another student?"

"Nobody could be that stupid."

"Do you have any better ideas?"

"Every idea is a better idea."

As they walked, arguing, they encountered a small class desk in the hallway with a sign:

HALLOWE'EN SWEETS,
COURTESY OF
HARMLESS HUFFLEPUFFS

On the desk next to the sign was a tray of orange-and-black wrapped sweets. Without paying them much attention, the boy who greatly resembled Dean Thomas tossed a few into his robes' pockets.

"What if he never had it to begin with?" he said, eventually.

"Then why would we have been sent—ah. To get rid of us." The one who looked like Seamus frowned. "Let's give it a few more weeks. If nothing turns up in that time, we'll... resort to the contingency plan."

"Sounds good," said the one who looked like Dean before eating a Sherbet Lemon. "Although last time, we got our—argh!" He doubled over, his insides twisting and writhing, his facial features moving, as if made from warm wax. The boy who greatly resembled Seamus cursed in a most un-childlike manner and pulled him into a nearby bathroom, safe from prying eyes. Within a few seconds, a man who had once looked like Dean sat, sagged against a cool tile wall.

"Amycus?" said the boy who looked like Seamus. "Amycus, are you okay? Lumos. Follow my wand." He moved the glowing wand tip slowly back and forth in front of his dazed eyes.

Amycus Carrow groaned uncomfortably, and looked at his hands. They were big and calloused; nothing like the small, dextrous hands he'd gotten used to.

"Mandrake root," he spat. "He's on to us; we must—agh!" he tried to stand, but he misjudged the length of his suddenly-altered legs and tripped.

"Just wait here," said the boy who was increasingly unlikely to be Seamus, "until you feel a bit better."

"No, we need to hide," he protested. "Someone will find us here."

"In this bathroom? Hah! Nobody's coming in here." The boy who looked like Seamus hesitated briefly. "So," he said finally, "Shall we use the contingency plan?"

"Lucius said—"

"Oh, Lucius said," the boy who looked like Seamus said mockingly. "You think we're doing this because of what Lucius said? No, we're here for what happens after. The Dark Lord will honour us above Malfoy—above, even, that mad, dead, Lestrange witch—when we are successful. Drink your Polyjuice and let's move. There's work to do."

o—o—o—o—o—o—o

Author's Notes: See, I'm not dead! I just have writer's block. As an attempted fix, I'm going to publish what I do have, i.e., this short chapter you just read, rather than sit on it until it's up to the usual length. Hopefully, this might bump me out of my current rut.

D&D Tip: This one's for all the optimizers out there. You won't always be in a party of players with the same play style as you, and their opinion can sometimes sour if you steal the show with an overpowered character. For some, it's a simple matter of making a less powerful character. If that works for you, then perfect. But if you're like me, you have a really hard time doing that. Optimization is fun. Trawling through rulebooks for that golden feat or item is very zen. There are two solutions I have discovered to this problem: the first, you start a character handicapped, and optimize to your heart's content from there. You play a lousy class (*cough*CW Samurai*cough*), or a poor class/race combo (half-orc sorc?), or with deliberately poor ability score allocation, and then you hit the ground running with the best feats, gear, etc. that you can find. That way, it's fun for everyone—you get the experience of playing a totally unique character that you've never done before (and it might result in optimization decisions you'd never have previously considered) and you won't generally outstrip the party too much.

The other solution is to play a buffer. Measure your character's success not in enemies you defeat, but in those that you help the party defeat. Try playing a bard and maximizing Inspire Courage, or a Cleric that doesn't use the normal CoDzilla tricks, a Marshal, or another support class. You get to optimize to the maximum, and your allies get to feel like gods of war. Just be careful not to fall into the trap of buffing yourself to turn yourself into an undefeatable killing machine. Also make sure you get a feel of the party's makeup before you invest too much in one buffing method or another. I tried this with a Bard, once, not realizing that the rest of the party would be a Psion, a Wizard, and a Cleric. I wound up being the only one taking advantage of my +5 Inspire Courage and Haste, and, well, overpowered everyone else more than ever.

D&D Tip #2: Shrink Item + Permanency is freaking cool. The possibilities are legion, but here's the first that came to mind: you can make your character a cloak of water that, on command, floods the room

Chapter 12: Hallowe'en Masks

"Why do they call you Longbottom, Longbottom?" Miles Bletchley sneered.

"Yeah, more like Fatbottom," Flint said mockingly.

Neville pressed his back up against the wall, willing himself to just sink into it and be gone. Gone from this situation, this hallway, this school. No, not gone from Hogwarts. He loved Hogwarts. It was just some of the people in it that were the problem.

The thick bottom border of the mirror frame stabbed into his shoulder blades uncomfortably, but there wasn't much he could do about it; half the Slytherin Quidditch team was standing between himself and freedom.

"Or, or Dumbottom," Montague said. "Because he's so dumb."

The worst part—well, not the worst part, but one of the many bad parts—was that their insults weren't even clever. Neville would feel much better about himself, on the whole, if he was made miserable by clever and biting insults, rather than this rather run-of-the-mill fare. But the truth was that it hurt all the same. He wished it didn't. He wished he were stronger, like his Gran always said. Tougher. Harder. Braver. Smarter. More like Harry Potter. Merlin, but she went on about Harry Potter.

But what would Harry Potter do? Duel three wizards, each more advanced than he, all at once? He could try it. He might even win; after all, he'd been getting better in Lockhart's Club. He knew he was. He'd even managed to disarm the vaunted Harry Potter four times out of ten. But it wasn't always that easy. It wasn't a question of skill, or of size, or even of numbers. The problem was in his head, but knowing that just made it worse. The spiral of thoughts locked him into immobility. Why are they picking on me? Because they know I won't fight back. Why don't I fight back? Because I'm scared. Why am I scared? Because I'm weak. Why am I weak? Because I'm scared. Rinse and repeat. Weak. Scared. Useless. Pathetic. An embarrassment to the family name. The insults Neville created for himself were far worse, and hit far more squarely, than any that these braindead Slytherins could ever have devised.

He didn't want to fight them; he just wanted them to be gone. To just go away.

"Go away?" Flint said incredulously. "You want me to 'go away?'" he made little air quotes with his fingers mockingly. Neville felt lightheaded. He couldn't believe he'd said that out loud. "Did you hear that, boys? What do you say—should we go away?" Bletchley and Montague just laughed raucously in response. Flint drew his wand and held it at Neville's throat. "And how are you going to make us?"

"I—I'll duel you," Neville whispered. Oh Merlin, I'm so dead...

"I'm sorry, I couldn't hear that," Flint said. "I couldn't hear you, Fatbottom."

"I said I'll duel you!" Neville practically screamed. "Stupefy! Petrificus Totalus! Immobulus!" Neville didn't even have a wand out; he just screamed random curses that popped into his head. He knew he was as good as dead anyway, so why not?

Neville was through all of the duelling curses and hexes that he knew and was into the minor jinxes when he realized he was still alive enough to shout. He opened his eyes. Flint was staring just above his head, completely immobile. Cautious in case this was some sort of trick, Neville slowly slid down to the ground. Meeting no resistance, he crawled between their legs to freedom. Becoming convinced that this was not some peculiar ruse, he looked closer at his tormentors. Flint, Montague, and Bletchley were all looking into the mirror that Neville had been pressed up against. What had they seen? He drew his wand—much good it had been earlier—and held it up to Flint's face, trying to get it to match the angle of his eyes as best he could. With some difficulty, he managed to make it stay, wedged between the Slytherin's ear and head.

"Lumos." A thin ray of light shone out of the tip of his wand and was reflected off of the mirror. Curious, Neville followed it down the hall, where it rebounded off of a polished statue, followed by a brass candlestick, around the corner to an iron windowframe, and, finally, coming to an end in the middle of a completely empty hallway in front of a statue of a lost-looking wizard titled 'Boris the Bewildered.'

"You're not the only one, mate," Neville muttered, then returned to reclaim his wand. Best tell Dumbledore or McGonagall, he thought. Just as he turned to leave, a new thought struck him.

But first... he grinned, drawing his wand.

o—o—o—o

"So, what are you going to dress up as for the feast this evening?" Hannah asked Milo as they walked past the lake, her breath visible in the chill October air. Around the lake, other students were enjoying the clear (by the standards of Scottish autumn) weather. Cedric and some other Hufflepuffs were tossing a Quaffle around, Lavender Brown and the Patil twins were chatting with a group of other NPCs about something unimportant, and some upper-year Ravenclaws were already cramming for their NEWTs, despite the exams being most of a year away. Ravenclaws could be like that sometimes.

"Haven't given it a moment's thought, to be honest," Milo admitted. "I've been too busy worrying about what might happen today."

"You mean like when the Troll escaped last year?" Hannah asked.

"Exactly like that. Hallowe'en's too significant for too many reasons for today to go smoothly."

Hannah shrugged. "I'd say we'll be ready for whatever happens, if anything does. Between the Duelling Club and your Hellipedes, I've never been more confident about my magic. I mean, watch this. Look at that fish for a second." She pointed at a pike swimming near the surface of the dark lake. "Stupefy!" There was a red flash, and the pike froze, floating to the surface. "See? I've been practicing. We all have."

"No kidding." Milo was impressed; he hadn't even seen her draw her wand. "Oh, this reminds me. Here, I've got something for you." Milo rooted about in his extradimensional belt, then pulled out a standard Hogwarts robe.

"I'm guessing it's not just an extra change of clothes?" Hannah said, looking at it curiously.

"It's magically enhanced," Milo explained. "Roughly as tough as steel. Should keep you safe from claws, fangs, and pointy sticks—oh, and Redcaps, in case we see one of those guys again—but it won't do anything against magic."

"That would explain why I saw Ron and Harry wailing at each other with Beaters' bats, and laughing, then," Hannah said, taking the robes. "I was wondering about that." She frowned. "I, er, appreciate the present, but these are a size small."

"Don't worry," Milo said. "They resize to the wearer. You could be bigger than Hagrid and they'd still fit."

Hannah grinned. "You should have said that first, then! With any luck, that will be the more useful part. I'll never have to go to Madam Malkin's again!"

"Just make sure you wear them—and the amulet—pretty much all of the time. The amulet especially."

"Of course; I haven't taken it off since you gave it to me. I remember last Christmas, too." Hannah frowned. "This is going beyond your usual paranoia. What's going on?"

"The fact is, I don't know," Milo admitted. "And that scares me. There are people looking for something, but I don't have a single clue about what they're looking for. Why do they want it? What is it? What will happen if they find it?"

"Could it be the Philosopher's Stone, again?" Hannah suggested.

"Possibly," Milo said. He was surprised he hadn't considered that. "I'm pretty sure Dumbledore moved it after last year, though. I'd always assumed it was this adventure's MacGuffin, but I suppose it could be the MacGuffin of the whole campaign."

"Elaine MacGuffin? The fourth-year Hufflepuff girl?"

"Nah, the magic-artifact-thingy that everybody wants. The origin of its name is lost in the depths of time. Frankly, I'd assumed it was Harry. You know, something-something-key-to-defeating-the-Dark-Lord or whatever. Although Dumbledore did say it had more to do with Harry's mother..." Milo frowned. He felt as if he might be on to something, but he'd need more time to work it out. "On top of all that, there's this whole Chamber of Secrets thing with Peeves. Annoying as he is, why an ancient monster would sneak out of hiding to take out an NPC who was clearly intended as comic relief is beyond me."

"And you probably want to find a way to get home, right?" Hannah asked.

"Well, yeah, eventually," Milo said vaguely. He hadn't actually thought about home in quite some time. "But I'm sure they can live without me for a while yet. I think I'm needed here more."

Hannah grinned. "You, sir, are correct. Whatever would we do if we didn't have you to overcomplicate things for us?"

"I'm sure you'd find something to do to fill up the time," Milo said. "Quidditch or infighting or whatnot."

Across the lake, a huffing, puffing Hufflepuff Milo didn't recognize ran up to the Quidditch players. Whatever he said, it surprised Cedric enough that—for the first time Milo had seen—he fumbled the Quaffle when it was passed to him. A few seconds later, they were running into the castle, followed shortly by Lavender, the Patils, and the others.

Hannah frowned. "Maybe we should check out what's going on?"

Even a few Ravenclaws pulled themselves away from their studies to follow the crowd.

"Yeah," Milo said. "Definitely."

They followed the growing throng of students, pushing against each other to be the first to reach their intended goal—whatever it was. Over the din, Milo managed to snatch the occasional glimpse of what sounded like relevant information.

"... entire hallway disappeared..."

"... almost the entire Slytherin team..."

"... with me..."

"... ears to cumquats..." Milo frowned. He must have failed a Listen check on that one. At some point in the push, he lost track of Hannah. As the movement was starting to slow and the bodies were packed even more tightly together, someone grabbed Milo's arm roughly.

"I said, come with me!" It was Ron. Surprised, Milo let his feet carry him away from the crowd and the noise, down a side corridor to the main staircase. Around the corner, Harry and Hermione were waiting impatiently.

"What's going on?" Milo asked.

"So you finally got him, then?" Harry asked irritably, ignoring his question.

"There were a lot of people," Ron said defensively. "It was hard to pick him out."

"What's happening?" Milo asked again.

"It's Dean and Seamus," Hermione said. "Ron heard them say they were going to... kill somebody. We thought we'd best grab you."

"Fair enough," Milo shrugged. "Lead on." Without another word, they hustled to the entrance to Gryffindor tower.

"Password?" the fat lady asked.

"Friendly Melons," Milo replied, and she swung open. Milo glanced back at his friends. "Wands out, people."

Inside, things looked fairly normal. The Weasley twins were playing wizard chess near the window, Neville was reading the Potions textbook on an armchair, and Dean and Seamus were chatting conspiratorially in the corner.

"Hey, dirtbags!" Milo shouted at the two. "Hope you enjoy a face full of Glitterd—"

"Incarcerous," Fred cast, and Milo's arms were suddenly tied behind his back with ropes, ruining the spell. More ropes tied his legs together at the ankles.

"What the hell, Fred?" Milo asked angrily. "Yo! Gryffindors! Dean and Seamus over there are like, seriously bad news!"

"Are we?" Dean asked, standing up. "Are we, really? And why is that, little boy?"

"Well, there's all the skulking about, the fact that Ron here overheard you plotting murder, and the 'little boy' you just threw out there didn't help your case any, either."

"He's got a point, Dean," Seamus said. "We do sound like—what was it? Ah, yes. 'Seriously bad news.'"

"Oh, he has no idea how bad, Seamus," Dean said.

"You're right, Dean. Why don't we show him?" Seamus walked up to Milo, and stared him in the eye. Then, without warning, his fist caught Milo in the jaw, knocking him to the ground awkwardly.

"Hey! Hermione, kick their asses!" Milo said, spitting blood on the red-and-gold carpet. Why wasn't anyone doing anything? "Harry? Ron?" But nobody moved.

"Oh, I've wanted to do that for months, little boy," Seamus muttered.

"Listen to him calling for help, Seamus," Dean said. "He thinks he's surrounded by friends."

Oh, crap.

Milo's mind raced, but it didn't take him long to guess what happened. Of course. Whatever it was that happened downstairs had been a big enough distraction to draw everyone from the Common Room down to take a look. There had certainly been enough people that Milo would believe every single Hogwarts student was down there. So, everyone currently in the room with him was some sort of plant. Now, the question remained: were they his actual friends, controlled by the Imperius Curse, or were they someone else using a Polyjuice potion?

Milo felt his lips twitch up into a smile, despite everything. "Well," he said. "Crap. Looks like you've got me."

"Indeed," not-Seamus said. "Now, tell me, where have you hidden the book?"

Great. Another one of these conversations.

"Somewhere safe," Milo said vaguely. He had no idea what book they were talking about. "I'm willing to make a deal, but first, you must answer one question."

"Acceptable. Ask your question; but be warned: if we even think you are casting a spell, you will be dead before you hit the floor."

"I understand. Now, my friends—the people you're disguised as—are they safe?"

"For now."

"Good." So they were disguise as, rather than possessing, his friends. He could use Divinations to track them down later. In fact, with the exception of Dean and Seamus, it was more than likely that they were all in the castle, completely oblivious to the events in the Common Room. These people, whoever they were, could simply have pulled a hair from their marks' robes or pillows at their leisure to use for a Polyjuice potion. Not only was that what Milo would have done, it's what he had done; he'd already owled to Cog small paper packets with hairs taken from, at most recent count, one-third of the Hogwarts student body. "The wall behind me is an Illusion," Milo said.

The funny thing about Illusions is that, once you know they're not real, they turn transparent. The most obvious use of this trick is to create a one-way window from which to spy or snipe, but, in Milo's opinion, that was far from the only one.

Anyone who heard his declaration would notice, if they were paying very close attention, the south wall of the Gryffindor Common Room move almost a tenth of a millimetre as the Illusory Wall flickered away. And even if they weren't paying attention, they'd notice the massive, garish, magenta-and-cyan glow-in-the-dark text that was suddenly visible.

THE CHAMBER OF MUNCHKINRY HAS BEEN OPENED.
ENEMIES OF ABSURDLY OVERPOWERED ARCANE MAGIC, BEWARE.

Post Scriptum: this text is exactly twenty five words long, thanks.

"Wh—"

A small viper, sepia-toned like an old photograph, leapt out of the wall from a discreet sigil concealed in the final period of the message. It flew towards not-Seamus like a bullet before vanishing in a puff of dun smoke in front of his startled eyes.

As the smoke cleared, a shimmering amber field became visible, surrounding the immobile not-Seamus. Unless somehow dispelled, he would remain trapped there, in stasis, for about a week and a half.

"Merlin's beard!" not-Hermione cursed, staring at the frozen not-Seamus.

"Avada—" not-Neville began casting.

"No, you fool!" not-Dean shouted. "We need him alive!"

Good to know, Milo noted.

"But he used magic!" not-Neville protested. "He could kill us all!"

"Idiot! That was clearly a premade trap—if he could do it to all of us, he would have. Use your mind! He's powerless."

Milo had to make a formidable Bluff check to bite down laughter. Whoever thought that a Wizard was powerless simply because he was surrounded by enemies, alone, unarmed, and tied down in the middle of a room had Bad Things coming in their near future. Not that a Wizard who could speak was ever really unarmed, of course.

"So, this book," Milo said, "I don't suppose you could describe it for me?"

"Don't get cute with me, boy," not-Dean snapped. "You know very well what book I'm talking about."

"You're absolutely certain of that?" Milo asked.

"Obviously. Stop stalling for time. You have thirty seconds."

Milo frowned. Maybe he did have this book they wanted. There was only one book he carried around of any magical significance, and that was his spellbook. Maybe they thought they could learn Arcane magic from it?

"It won't work for you," Milo said seriously. "It'd be as useful as a notebook full of scribbles."

"I'll be the judge of that," not-Dean said. "Just hand it over before things get... unpleasant."

Right, because being sprawled on the floor with my hands tied up isn't unpleasant at all.

"It will only work for me," Milo repeated. "It's mine."

Not-Dean's eyes widened. "You don't mean that you..."

"Yes! Yes I do!" Milo wasn't quite sure what not-Dean was getting at, but he seemed to be making progress here. Any attempt to use his spellbook was a fool's errand.

"Then you'd best come with us," not-Dean said.

Milo laughed. "I'm not going anywhere with you." This conversation was getting weird, fast.

"Then I'm sure you'll understand my predicament. If you don't back up your claim by either producing the book or coming with us, I'll use more direct methods to determine the truth, and I don't think either of us want it to come to that."

What claim? What the Hells was going on?

"Torture won't help you," Milo said, frantically trying to think of a plan. "Because I'm not Milo. I'm really, uh, that guy." He nodded at not-Neville completely at random.

"Who, Avery?" not-Dean asked. "What nonsense is this?" not-Dean aimed his wand steadily at Milo. "I'm done with this. You'll tell us the truth, now."

"Yeah! Avery! We switched by some kind of—"

"Crucio," not-Dean cast.

"Translocation Trick." Milo muttered. In a rather disorienting manner, he suddenly found himself looking like Neville and staring at, well, himself from the other side of the room.

"Wait! Stop!" the unfortunate person (Avery?) disguised as Neville disguised as Milo gasped between tortured screams. "I'm really Avery! Avery!" Milo tried to think back to where he'd heard that name before.

"He's lying," Milo said. "I'm Avery!"

"Where is the book?" not-Dean shouted at the writhing Avery.

"How the hell should I know?" Avery shrieked back. "I'm one of you!"

"That is the least believable lie I've ever heard!"

Milo shifted uncomfortably as Avery writhed on the floor, straining against the ropes that tied him down. Killing orcs was one thing, but this was... wrong. Torture was explicitly stated to be an Evil act in the rules, and Milo felt it was a flimsy defence to say that he wasn't the one doing the torture; he had simply arranged events such that someone else would be tortured while he waited, doing nothing. The fact that the victim looked exactly like him didn't help matters any.

"Ready an action, Mordy," Milo whispered to his Familiar. "We'll take them next turn."

The Translocation Trick hid Milo's extradimensional belt, so anyone looking closely would see Mordy's head and arms pop out of seemingly-nowhere.

3...2...1...

"Shatter." Not-Dean's wand exploded with a thunderclap, saving Avery from his torment. Briefly. Mordy, using bracers enchanted with Launch Item, fired a marked knut into the centre of the room. The rat squinted, using his goggles-enhanced Spot check to read the tiny rune at a distance.

The coin exploded in a purple-green burst, taking most of the room with it. The windows shattered outwards, and most of the furniture was reduced to splinters. People disguised as most of his best friends were sent flying across the room.

"Mercy!" the one disguised as Harry Potter gasped, cradling a clearly broken arm. "Master, have mercy!"

Death Eaters—Milo remembered where he'd heard the name 'Avery' before—were sprawled around the room, battered and broken. But alive. Another volley from Mordy would change that. He knew that it was the right decision. If they lived, they'd go on, serving Malfoy and Voldemort, until they were thrown in Azkaban or killed. It was the smart choice. Milo looked at the Death Eater disguised as Ron, whimpering on the floor. He looked at the Death Eater disguised as Hermione, whose face was covered in blood. He looked at the Death Eater disguised as Harry, begging for mercy at Milo's feet.

He looked at himself—Avery—on the floor, unconscious.

"Everybody leave," Milo said quietly. "Just go. If I see any of you again, I'll probably kill you." Of course, they were in disguise, highlighting the absurdity of his threat. He didn't know who most of them were, but at this point, he didn't really care.

"A—Accio Broomsticks," the Death Eater who looked like Harry said, and a tightly wrapped bundle of brooms flew in through the window a few seconds later.

It took some doing to get them all on brooms, but a few minutes later, they were gone, and Milo was left in a room with his rat, an amber-trapped Death Eater, and pile of broken furniture.

o—o—o—o

Lucius Malfoy sealed the envelope to the Hogwarts board of directors before tying to an owl's waiting leg. All in all, he'd call the day a victory. Sure, his Death Eaters had been bloodied and defeated (and, more importantly, had failed in their mission). But really, he'd expected that. Their mission had served its purpose; it had distracted them from his lack of desire to bring the Dark Lord back and given them a new motive: revenge. They were mad enough about their humiliating defeat that they would question no orders that sent them up against that unnatural little child. And, now that they had returned home, he could stop blackmailing potion makers across Britain into making him Polyjuice. Of course, there was still the matter of what to do with the captured students, but Lucius was certain that, if they were found, he was removed enough from the situation that it wouldn't affect him in any real way.

But it was the surprising attack on Slytherin's Quidditch team that had been the real highlight of the day. Rich, pureblooded families across the country were crying for blood, and Lucius knew exactly how and where to channel that anger and fear. There were a not insignificant number of halfbloods and mudbloods, even those who were usually Lucius's enemies, who were joining the mob.

Power came from seizing opportunities when you found them, not from stubbornly sticking to outdated plans and causes, and this was an opportunity too good for Lucius to pass up. Come tomorrow morning, he would not trade places with Dumbledore for all the gold in Gringotts. Well, maybe he would. With that much gold, he could bribe his way out of any problem. But the sentiment still stood.

Lucius pulled out another sheet of parchment, this one intended for the Daily Prophet, and began writing.

As a concerned father and respected community leader, I am outraged at the flagrant disregard for student safety exhibited by Hogwarts's current administration...

It was almost too easy.

o—o—o—o—o—o—o

Author's Notes: I'm switching the update days to Fridays to better match my new schedule. If I don't find that that works, I might push it to Saturday or Sunday instead. Also, I've decided that the previous chapter's name ("Hallwe'en Masks") fits this chapter much better. So I've renamed Chapter 11 to "Trick or Treat" (which is a better name anyway, considering the events of the previous chapter) and I'm naming Chapter 12 "Hallowe'en Masks." Sorry for the confusion, as this is one of the problems in writing in a serial format: it can be awkward to go back and change things when you have a better idea.

D&D Tip: Though this one works equally well for pretty much any RPG. If you're doing one of those Showdown At High Noon-style walk ten paces, turn, and fire duels (or a quick-draw Single Stroke Battle), here's what you do for optimum coolness around the table: have one player count down, and at one, both contestants simultaneously roll attack, and initiative, and do all the addition of bonuses, etc., before declaring what happened. Then you roll damage.

This highlights the sudden, tense nature of the duel around the table in a satisfying way, while still following the rules to the letter.

Chapter 16: Equivalent Exchange

Their meeting wasn't exactly a secret, but then, they didn't exactly want anyone to find out about it, either.

Milo sat behind a small table in a dusty, long-unused office on the third floor, just around the corner from where a Troll had thrown him through a window a year earlier. The enormous oak tree he'd created was still there, blocking most of the hallway. To get to the room they were in, you had to squeeze between the rough bark and the still-damaged stone wall. It was as close to private as you could get in Hogwarts without resorting to one of the secret passages, of which Milo was still largely in the dark about, or without revealing certain tricks he had pulled with Illusory Wall.

Besides, he had his most trusted thug—

Milo felt a surge of irritation through the bond.

His most favoured minio—

The irritation increased.

His trusted, loyal companion through the years, who had never left his side in danger (except for that one time with the Acromantula), who had always come through for him, and who had recently been armed with magical high explosives, though, verily, he could deter threats with his bare fangs, stood watch outside the door.

Mordy seemed to have no problem with that description.

Across the table from him were a witch and a wizard. The first had a square jaw, close-cropped gray hair, a monocle, and a serious expression. The second was in his mid-thirties and looked like he had experienced as much stress in his life as a man five times his age. His robes were wrinkled as if he'd slept in them, but, judging by the dark bags under his eyes, that had been several days ago. His dark brown hair was prematurely streaked with silver, and he was drumming his fingers impatiently against the table.

"Are these precautions really necessary?" he asked irritably. "We're in a school, not a hostile nation."

Milo looked him in the eye. "Yes. They are," he said. "The new headmaster hates me. Hates me. He wouldn't care that what we're doing here could save lives, and he certainly doesn't care about your positions in the Ministry. He'd throw you out and give me another month's detention, regardless of the consequences. He's got Lucius on his side, which—"

"Which makes him untouchable, yes, we know," the witch said impatiently. "I'll be honest with you, boy. I'm only here because Albus Dumbledore called in a favour." She turned to face the wizard she'd brought with her. "And that means, Peasegood, that we follow his recommendations."

"Then why did you refuse my initial plan?" Milo asked.

The head of the Department of Magical Law Enforcement, Amelia Bones, sniffed.

"Because sneaking in by concealing ourselves in the back of a hay wagon hardly seemed appropriate," she said.

"It's always worked for me," Milo said. "But to each his own."

"Can we get on with this?" Peasegood asked, checking a pocket watch. "I have a wedding to get to in Wales."

"Oh?" Bones asked. "Whose?"

"A Muggle lad and a werewolf's," Peasegood said. "It was messy. Nearly a hundred witnesses."

"Well then, boy," Bones said to Milo. "As you can see, we are on a schedule. If you could bring out the alleged amulets?"

Milo pulled off his own Amulet of Protection from Evil and placed it on the table. Like most magic items, its physical appearance was generally unimportant, but this particular amulet took the form of a tiny kite shield of alternating silver-and-copper dangling from a solid steel chain. The last thing he wanted was something yanking it off in a scuffle. It was engraved with the Eye of Boccob, because anything in Milo's possession that couldn't double as a holy symbol in a pinch simply wasn't worth carrying. He was still keenly aware that Quirrell's vampires had yet to make an appearance.

"This is an Amulet of Protection," Milo said. He decided to drop the 'from evil' on recommendation from Hannah, as it sounded a tad melodramatic for most governments. "It will never tarnish or age, the chain will resize to fit the neck of any wearer—and I do mean any wearer—it provides minor defences against physical and magical attacks from, well, from bad people and creatures, makes the wearer untouchable by creatures summoned into existence by magic," Milo wished he'd remembered that in his duel with Draco, who seemed awfully fond of summoning snakes. "And, last, and most importantly, provides continuous and complete protection against all forms of magic that exercise mental control over the wearer." Milo was aware that he was handing a potentially extremely powerful tool over to the Ministry, but he didn't see that he had much choice. He desperately needed the money; spell research was hardly cheap, and he was deeply in debt with Harry. The ability to easily block an Unforgivable Curse was probably his greatest advantage on the local wizards, and, as such, he could sell it for the greatest profit. Besides, the Ministry seemed to, basically, be the good guys. They were sometimes obtuse and obstructive, sure, but he doubted they'd ever actually be actively hostile to him. He'd considered putting a back door into the amulets he sold to the ministry—a simple matter of deliberately making each amulet a cursed item with the Dependent drawback (such as 'the item only works whenever nobody within 30 feet has said "Krund the Barbarian Teaches Spelling" in the last sixty seconds'), but he'd decided against it. Too many Ministry officials were powerful wizards or witches, and too many powerful wizards and witches could apparently read minds. He doubted they would respond positively to deception of that variety.

Amelia Bones' mouth cracked into a brief smile, but Peasegood actually laughed.

"We've wasted our time here," Peasegood said, and stood to leave.

"Hold on," Bones said. "We've come this far. We should at least see this farce to its natural conclusion." Peasegood rolled his eyes and sat down, and Bones turned to look at Milo. "Do you know why I've brought Peasegood with me?" she asked.

Milo shrugged. "I figured it had something to do with interdepartmental politics," he said.

"No," Amelia Bones said. "It's because he's the best wizard I know when it comes to mental magic. He's our top Obliviator because of it, and with good reason." She reached down, picked up the amulet, and looked at it closely. Then she shrugged and fastened it about her neck. She looked at Peasegood and nodded.

"Fifteen," he said to her, drawing his wand. "Obliviate," he said with a quick flourish of his wand that seemed to be done entirely by muscle memory. "What number did I just tell you?"

"Fifteen," Bones answered. "Try again."

"Elephant. Obliviate. What animal—"

"Elephant."

"1492. Obliviate. What—"

"1492."

On and on it went. Peasegood listed dozens of names of places and historical figures, of animals and vegetables and minerals, and of dates and numbers and colours. After the first ten or so, he frowned and cast each spell with more effort, more concentration, and more precision. After another twenty, he insisted Bones turn over her wand, close her eyes, and face the wall. Nothing he tried made any difference.

"Well," he said eventually. "I'll bite. What did you do to my wand?"

"Nothing," Bones said with a frown. "Still, all this proves is the amulet is protected with an extremely powerful Shield Charm. Difficult, but hardly earthshaking. Still, this is very impressive, especially for a second-year student. Come back when you're of age, and we'll see what you can do then."

"Ms. Bones," Milo said with a touch of smugness, "when I said the amulet protects against continuous and complete protection against all forms of mental magic, I meant it. That amulet can go quite a bit further than Memory Charms."

Bones sighed. "Boy, I know what you're hinting at, and I can assure you that is quite impossible."

"We should test it," Peasegood said. Even he seemed surprised by his words. "I've never—never—seen a Shield Charm so handily defeat my magic before. Never. We should see how far this goes."

Bones sighed. "Very well." Then she removed the amulet.

"Won't you need that?" Milo asked.

"Boy," she said, "Bellatrix Lestrange herself couldn't get me with the Imperius Curse. Peasegood is good, but—no offence—he's not Bellatrix, God rest her soul." Milo was surprised; most of the wizards and witches in this world (and in his own) avoided religion the way that optimizers avoided Endurance and Run.

"No offence taken," Peasegood said. "I think the whole world gave a collective sigh of relief when she died last year."

"My point, boy, is that the only way for this amulet's alleged ability to block what I remind you is a theoretically unblockable curse is for us to cast it on you. Do you consent?"

Milo nodded, fastening the amulet around his neck.

"Very well. Arnold Peasegood, as head of the DMLE, I sanction the use of the Imperius Curse under the Responsible Use clause of the 1980 War Statute for the purposes of training and experimentation. I am legally obliged to remind you that misuse or abuse of this permission warrants an immediate life sentence in Azkaban. Do you understand?"

"I understand."

"Very well. Begin. Make him stand up and nothing else."

Peasegood looked at Milo and licked his lips nervously. "I'd hoped never to have to use this except against a fully trained wizard or witch." He took a deep breath. "Imperio."

Milo yawned somewhat theatrically.

Peasegood stared down at his wand in astonishment.

"Did he resist?" she asked.

"No," Peasegood said. He swallowed. "He didn't have to."

Bones stared at him in astonishment, then up at Milo, then back at Peasegood.

As Bones came to grips with what had just happened, Milo calmly reached into his Belt of Hidden Pouches and drew a large, heavy canvas sack, which he upturned on the table.

Thirty identical amulets poured onto the table.

"I think," she said slowly, "that we should keep this quiet—for the moment. If Lucius knew what these were for, he could block the purchase. Besides," she grinned. "I want the next dark wizard who tries to bewitch an Auror to be taken by surprise. Just wish I could guarantee I was there to see it..."

What followed was a negotiation. For almost the first time, Milo didn't regret prioritizing Charisma over Constitution at character creation, as it gave him a sorely-needed edge against the head of the DMLE, who bargained like a horse trader. She wanted them by the hundred, to equip every employee of the Ministry to begin with, and, eventually, the entire wizarding world, but Milo negotiated her down to a more reasonable number and a better price. Each amulet cost him two days of magical crafting (although his Homunculus, Cog, put in the actual hours), ten galleons' worth of salt, and a non-negligible amount of experience points.

That said, the gods themselves could hardly give him a better bargaining position. To them, these amulets represented complete protection against one of the greatest threats in the world. It was revolutionary. Game changing.

To him, it was a first-level spell and a pile of salt.

They were willing to pay a small fortune in gold for the necklaces (although, unfortunately, gold in this universe seemed to be quite a bit rarer and more valuable than gold in his). They eventually settled on twelve amulets a month, which left him enough time to work on items for himself and his party, at a hefty hundred galleons—equivalent in weight to six hundred and thirty gold pieces—per necklace. It was less than they were worth in his universe in terms of volume of gold, but factoring in the cheaper raw materials cost, the irritating and ubiquitous Adventurers-Sell-for-Half-Laws, and the relative value of gold, Milo figured he was coming out ahead by quite a bit. The first several months of that, however, would go to paying back Harry's generous loans over the last year and a bit.

"Did I ever tell you that I had to bail that boy out of Muggle prison this summer?" Peasegood said to Bones as they left.

"No, I must have missed that one."

"Funny story. Fortunately, nothing came of it..."

o—o—o—o

Together, Fiona, Travis, and Hannigan had brought six eyes, which seemed about one one-hundredth as many as they would be needing.

Self-stirring cauldrons. Eel's eyes. Potion bottles. Flying broomsticks (Fiona started feeling a bit self-conscious about the one in her hand). Wand shops. And... an ice cream parlour.

It was closed, presumably because Fortescue had a cold. Bit of a let-down, actually.

"This place looks right out of Tim Burton's fever dream," Travis said.

"With a bit of the pirate base from Hook thrown in," Fiona added.

There were buildings built on top of other buildings, inside other buildings, and in one notable case, upside-down and underneath another building. Individual shops and stalls followed no particular theme, having apparently been built up to several centuries apart. Iron Age huts and red-roofed Roman structures shared walls with wooden lean-tos and crooked Renaissance-era towers. Diagon Alley seemed to be as old as London. Older, maybe.

"This place is not up to code," Hannigan grumbled. "Pick a code. Any code. This place is not up to it. The whole lot ought to be condemned."

"Ah," Travis stammered. He looked a bit pale.

"Yes?" Hannigan asked.

"That little old lady over there—the one outside the Apothecary—she, uh... The sign says she's selling dragon liver."

Fiona and Hannigan stared where he pointed in stunned silence.

"It... must be metaphorical," Fiona said. "Flavourful. Probably a local delicacy. Pub I used to go to in Glasgow had a drink they called Dragon's Breath. Must be like that." It must be. No way... no way could there be actual dragons. Magic was one thing, but dragons? Fiona was beginning to feel that they might be in a little bit over their heads.

"Yes," Hannigan said. "What the Serg— er, what the witch civilian said. Let's carry on with our first objective. I mean errand. Our first errand."

Near as they could tell, Diagon Alley was basically a single (if somewhat twisty) line without any major intersections or branches—except for one, which a black sign declared in black paint was called 'Knockturn Alley,' which, as police, they decided to avoid without significant backup. They had a sense for that sort of thing. In theory, this should have made finding their target—777 Diagon Alley—a cinch. Just walk forwards as the numbers go up, or turn around if they go down.

Unfortunately, the address numbers—those buildings which had them—seemed to be completely at random. A robes shop numbered '1' was directly adjacent to a wand shop whose address seemed to be composed of thirteen thirteens.

It was while searching for the Daily Prophet's office, their eyes sideways, up, and backwards searching for the address, that Fiona bumped into a child. He was maybe nine or ten years old, and had on a child-size robe with a floppy, wide hat.

"Excuse me!" Fiona said, and stepped to move around him.

"Whoa!" the boy said. "Nice broomstick! I've never seen one like it! Is it foreign?"

Fiona looked at the broom substitute she held in her hand. If she got out of this, she was keeping Sprocket on a dry food ration for a week as punishment.

"Foreign?" Fiona asked in her best Wicked Witch of the West voice. "It's from a place so far away it would addle your little mind to even begin to attempt to comprehend where it is!" Okay, so the line sounded way better in her head.

"Bet it's Italian," the boy said. "And it's bewitched to look like a mop, too!"

A middle-aged, anxious-looking witch hurried around a twist in the road.

"Oliver!" she called. "What did I tell you about wandering off? Come here." She turned to face Fiona. "Sorry, miss. He's always doing that."

"Wait!" Hannigan said as she turned to leave. He fished about in his robe pockets before producing a photograph. "Have you seen this boy?" he asked. "He has a distinctive scar, and may be in the company of a woman named Lily Potter."

The witch looked at the picture in disbelief for a moment before rolling her eyes.

"Yes, ha ha, very funny," she said, and made a face as if Hannigan had made a joke in particularly poor taste. "Have a nice day, then," and hustled off, her child in tow.

"That was odd," Hannigan said after she left.

It took half an hour to find the Prophet's office, a rather boring-looking square building nestled between an owl post office (that's right—owl post office) and a book store. Along the way, Hannigan accosted random passersby with his picture of Harry Potter with variations of the same questions. All seven of them thought it was some kind of joke.

"Wonder if I'm asking the wrong questions?" Hannigan mused. "Ah, well. That was objective two, in any case. On to objective one." He pushed open the plain glass and wood door to enter a plain-looking office. There were a few deceptively comfortable-looking chairs along the wall, with a few magazines for bored adults and some toys for bored children. In short, it was like every office Fiona had ever been in, which she felt just went to show, although she wasn't quite sure what it went to show.

A bored-looking witch sat behind the counter with her feet on the desk, reading a magazine called Witch Weekly. A handsome, blond man on the cover winked at her when she looked at it.

"God, but that's weird," she muttered to herself.

"I'm sorry?" The witch behind the counter said, although her tone indicated otherwise. "What did you want, then?"

Hannigan stepped up to her.

"We're here to take out a subscription," he said.

"Right," the woman said, holding out her palm. She hadn't taken her eyes off of the magazine. "That'll be one knut up front, and another per delivery."

"I'm sorry, did you say a newt?" Hannigan asked. Sure, eyes of newt were mentioned in Hamlet, but... seriously? If these wizards and witches used actual newts as currency, Fiona was going home and never leaving. A world where people used newts to buy newspapers was not a world Fiona wanted to take part in anymore.

"You deaf, mister?" the woman asked. "Not a newt, a knut. Kah-noot."

"Right," Hannigan said. "I seem to be fresh out of those. I don't suppose you could direct me to—"

"Gringotts is just a few minutes to the left," the lady said, pointing, unhelpfully, to the right.

"Well, we'll just drop by... Gringotts... and return presently," he said.

By process of deduction, they determined 'Gringotts,' whatever that was, was probably to the right, not the left, seeing as how that was the way they'd come from and they hadn't seen it. Probably. You never knew, in this place.

Unlike the Daily Prophet headquarters, Gringotts was quite easy to spot. It was a white marble, ancient looking building with scarlet-and-gold banners. In addition to being a very pretty building, it was also obviously designed for a siege. The windows had steel bars over them, and the burnished bronze doors looked like they were actual, solid bronze. Fiona didn't doubt that, in addition to the merely physical defences, the building had its share of magical ones as well.

As she drew nearer, however, her attention was pulled from the building. In fact, it became very hard to notice anything at all, save for the small... individual standing in front of the doors.

He (she? it?) was wearing pristine scarlet-and-gold livery, and... well. Fiona wasn't really looking at its (her? his?) clothes. The... thing... was small. Like, hobbit-sized small. That was where the resemblance ended. Rather than furry feet, a plump belly and a cheerful smile, this creature was kelp-green, covered in little warts and bumps, and below its upturned, pig-like nose was a scowl worthy of... worthy of... something really good at scowling. The wicked, hooked teeth definitely helped.

"Jesus Christ," Travis swore. "Is that a... an..."

"Orc?" Hannigan suggested.

"More of a kobold, really," Travis said.

"So, we should be able to take, like, a million of them each, right?" Fiona said. "I mean, the guys in the book could, and they didn't even have guns."

"Yeah, well," Hannigan said. "Neither do we. Shall we?" With that, Hannigan walked determinedly over to the creature.

Fiona swallowed and followed. Travis hesitated for a moment, then walked behind her.

The three of them put on their most important, businesslike looks and walked confidently through the doors. Behind the bronze doors were another set, this one made of silver. Fiona marvelled at them. If they were pure silver, and solid, their value would be... incalculable. It didn't take long, however, for her instincts to kick in. Nobody had the kind of money to make doors out of silver and consider it worthwhile. Nobody legitimate, anyway. This, of course, begged the question: where the heck were these creatures getting their cash from?

Another pair was standing just behind the silver doors. Probably guards, Fiona noted, taking into account their stance, their crossed arms, and their simultaneously suspicious and disregarding expression. They have the look. They weren't visibly armed, but it wasn't as if that meant anything. They were down the rabbit hole, now. The locals could have all kinds of weird powers. Heck, Fiona herself wasn't armed, but that hardly meant she wasn't dangerous, if it came to that.

Travis let out a low whistle as they entered the next room, and Fiona could see why. It was huge. Like, St. Paul's cathedral huge. The floors and walls were of white marble, with a large, misty fountain in the centre of the room. Creatures literally beyond count—she stopped counting at seventy-eight, and didn't think she'd accounted for half—scurried about, looking busy. Several had handcarts piled with what she could only describe as treasure. Gold and silver in any combination of bullion, coins, jewelry, and ornaments you could name. There were also precious stones in abundance. Fiona had never seen anything she'd felt compelled to use the word 'jewel' to describe before she saw one of the little green fellows holding up a ruby the size of Sprocket's head. There was enough money in here to buy actual nations—and Fiona doubted this was the extent of it. Everything in this room was in transit from one place to another; massive doors leading to dark corridors surrounded them. Anything could be down there.

If anything, the security around the place seemed light. Which meant Fiona had to be doubly on her guard—something was evidently protecting this place, and it was clearly enough to deter would-be thieves. Magical thieves, at that.

"Don't gawk," Hannigan said. "We'll only draw attention to ourselves."

They located a small line of ordinary-looking people organized by a velvet rope in one corner below a sign marked CURRENCY EXCHANGE. Guessing this was their destination, they formed up at the back of the line.

The people, most of whom were wearing simple street clothes, were handing the orc-kobold-thing money (mostly pounds, but some had francs or dollars) in exchange for coins of silver, gold, and bronze.

"Thank goodness nobody told Goldfinger about this place," Travis murmured. "It makes Fort Knox look like a tin of pennies."

As their turn came up, Hannigan took a half step in front of them.

"Excuse me, ah, sir," he said to the creature behind the counter, "how much for one knut?"

The creature gave them a flat stare for a moment.

"Serious customers only," it snarled. "Next!" it called.

"Wait!" Hannigan said. The creature stopped and looked at him. Hannigan turned to Travis and Fiona. "Right, turn out your pockets, lads," he said. Travis sighed, and they pulled out their wallets. Between them, they had fifty-eight pounds, forty-four pence, and a Canadian dollar.

"My sister lives in Montreal," Travis shrugged.

"How many can we get for all of this?" Hannigan asked.

The creature's eyes flicked over it for an instant.

"Eleven galleons, ten sickles, and fourteen knuts—after surcharge," he said. Either it was extremely talented at unit conversions, or it was making the numbers up completely.

"Sorry, is he selling us a fleet of ships, farm equipment, and lizards?" Travis whispered to Fiona. The creature, however, evidently heard him. It rolled its eyes.

"Galleons," it said, holding up a shining gold coin. "Sickles," it held up a slightly smaller silver coin. "And knuts," it held up a bronze coin.

"Ah, of course," Hannigan said. "But could we get, hmm, three of those sickles in knuts?"

Fiona looked at the coins the creature counted out and thought for a moment.

"So it's, what, about five quid to a galleon?" she asked.

"Yes," said the creature, who was still counting.

"So they're not pure gold, then," she reasoned.

The creature shot her a withering look that made Fiona reflexively shift her weight into a fighting stance. The thing had malice in its eyes.

"None of your kind has ever seen purer," it snarled. "Or ever will."

Hannigan nudged her with his elbow and made silencing gestures.

"Wait, hang on," she said. "That's way below the value of gold to pounds. So what's to stop these people from melting the coins down and selling them at enormous mark-up as raw bullion?"

The creature stared at her as if she was a total imbecile. Its jaws moved as if it was trying to form words, but could not grasp the monumental stupidity of her question.

"I would not recommend defacing goblin gold," was all it said. Fiona made a minor leap of intuition and concluded that if this was a bank stuffed with goblin gold and little green people, the little green people were probably goblins.

"Thank you," Fiona said. "Just wondering."

They filled their pockets full of goblin gold, silver, and bronze and hurried out.

"Oh, I would just love to sic a couple of crown auditors on them," Hannigan said. "Who wants to bet they're not adhering to the Banking Act? And I bet they've never paid their taxes."

"No deal. Where'd they get all that gold, I wonder?" Travis asked.

"Probably hauled it out of Moria," Fiona muttered. "What do you reckon they're going to do with our money? They can't exactly walk down to the financial sector and invest it."

"You can get pretty far just over the phone these days," Hannigan said. "And they could always hire a human to do it for them, in any case."

They dropped by the Daily Prophet again and took out a subscription for Fiona's flat (she was the only one of the three who lived alone, and as such wouldn't have to explain the avian post to her family/roommates, except Sprocket, who Fiona thought would have no more objection to daily owl delivery than she would to daily pizza delivery).

"One last thing," Hannigan said to the witch after they'd filled out the forms (with quills on parchment, not that Fiona was terribly surprised. She doubted anything could surprise her anymore.)

The witch looked up from her magazine for the first time, stared him dead in the eye, and blew an enormous pink bubble of gum. It popped, echoing through the room.

"Yes?" she asked.

"What can you tell me about this boy?" Hannigan held up the photograph.

The witch stared at it, then pointed at the wall behind them. On the wall was a large poster:

THE BOY WHO LIVED, a FACTUAL and ENTERTAINING biography of HARRY POTTER: available all places books are sold.

Fiona, Travis, and Hannigan said words then that small children ought not to hear.

"Book store next?" Hannigan asked. Not waiting for a response, he answered himself. "Book store next."

Flourish and Botts was, well, a bookshop. Frankly, after the goblin bank, it was disappointingly mundane. Sure, the subject of the books was extraordinary—and the books themselves were something to see; many of them were leather bound with beautifully embossed titles—but, all in all, it was sort of a letdown.

That handsome man from the magazine cover, apparently named Gilderoy Lockhart, was on posters all over the place, advertising his autobiography, Magical Me.

"Looks a bit like Kenneth Branagh, don't you think?" Fiona mused, staring at a life-size portrait of him.

"Nah," Hannigan said. "He must be, what, ten years older than Kenneth Branagh."

They split up to cover the bookstore as quickly as possible. They started with every book on Harry Potter they could find—and there were a surprisingly large number, for a missing twelve-year-old—threw in a couple of books on wizarding history (it was a sign of the things she had seen that day that Fiona did raised no objections to the apparent existence of the word 'wizarding'), and a more-or-less random selection of spellbooks. The last was Fiona's idea. If they could learn what these wizards were capable of, they could more adequately develop counter-measures. Against the darkness of the unknown, the only light is knowledge.

Upon tallying the prices, they put back several of the books on Harry Potter, before leaving with their pockets considerably heavier but decided less clink-y.

Once outside, Hannigan stopped and took a deep, satisfied breath.

"Savour this moment, lads. Er, lad. And lady. It's not every day that you can just go to a bookstore and buy critical information in your investigation for forty quid and change."

"What's next, then?" Fiona asked.

"We head home and do a little homework," Hannigan said.

"But what if we missed something?" Travis said. "There's loads here we haven't even looked at, yet."

Hannigan grinned broadly. "That's the best part, isn't it?" he said. "We can just walk right in here. Aside from the magic, do you see any security? Me neither. And besides," he added, "if anything comes up, Fiona here will be the first to know. She's on their mailing list."

Chapter 17: Remedial Divinations

The door to the Hog's Head Inn slammed shut behind the black-hooded newcomer, causing icicles to fall from the roof outside. The other patrons gave the newcomer, ahem, icy glares as the wave of cold air hit them, though the roaring hearth soon made them forget their climatological worries. The newcomer, androgynous and unidentifiable beneath the loose, silk robe looked around the inn, taking in the handful of chilled patrons, the grizzled, aged landlord, the ancient oak tables and bar. It was impossible to be certain without seeing his or her face, but something about the newcomer's bearing radiated contempt. Rapidly-melting snow was brushed away by black-gloved hands, falling to the floor with not a trace of concern for the innkeeper's floorboards, and the newcomer sat down at the bar next to another mysterious, black-robed stranger. The similarities began and ended at the colour of their wardrobes and their unidentified nature. Where the first robed figure's clothes were immaculate, tailored, and very, very expensive, the second was shabby. The second's robes were battered, faded black canvas spotted with poorly sewn-on patches of subtly different shades and materials from the base cloth, which was hardly visible. His or her robes were a tattered mess at the hem, as if they had been walked on.

The landlord passed each of them a firewhisky without a word. This sort of behaviour was not uncommon at the Hog's Head Inn.

"It appears," the first said in a slow, light drawl, "That things are going rather well for you." The newcomer somehow managed to, without any facial expression whatsoever, convey a sneer simply with the cadence and delivery.

"Well enough," the other said. This one didn't need any fancy oratorical tricks. The shrug was sufficient.

The newcomer took a sip of firewhisky. A brief flash of long, white-blond hair was visible as the hood tilted back slightly.

"Rather... impressive, don't you think? Your sudden ascent, that is," the newcomer pushed. "Almost as if you had... assistance."

"And I suppose we both know who to thank for that 'assistance.'" The stranger left the firewhisky sitting where the landlord had placed it.

"Yes," the newcomer drawled. "We do, at that." The newcomer left that hanging in the air for a moment before continuing. "I must say," the newcomer said, "that I'm rather surprised by you. You appear to be keeping secrets. You know how I feel about... secrets."

There was a loaded silence for several seconds. Then, something slight but significant changed in the stranger's posture. A gloved hand shot out from under the tattered robes, and seized the firewhisky glass. A moment later, it was slammed down on the table. Empty.

"You mean it wasn't you?" the stranger said, choking slightly.

"It wasn't you?" the newcomer gasped.

The two of them stared at each other from under their hoods for a tense second.

"I have to—"

"Questions to ask—"

In an instant, their bar stools had tumbled to the ground and both were gone.

"Buggers didn't pay," the landlord grumbled, watching the door slam shut behind them.

o—o—o—o

The scheduling of Quidditch practice times had always been a continual problem at Hogwarts. It tended to rain more-or-less three seasons a year at Hogwarts, and those three seasons, unfortunately, corresponded very closely to the school term. The rare dry day that rolled around every few weeks was highly prized by Quidditch players of all houses. However, with four teams and only one pitch, there was invariably something of a squabble for who would be the one to get the field.

Various headmasters over the years had different solutions to this problem. Most solutions involved either random chance, such as a flipped sickle (which has the unexpected problem of being hardly random at all. Keep in mind: actual magic), or requiring teams to book the field ahead of time on a first-come-first-serve basis (a practice favoured by Dumbledore), or even by sharing the pitch between multiple opposed teams at once (this 'hardly ever' resulted in 'accidental' injuries).

The newly-raised Headmaster Snape had his own, original take on the matter. He solved the problem by means of a rotating schedule in order to guarantee fairness for everyone.

This announcement caused something of an uproar in the Gryffindor Common Room, which was starting to smell (Snape had cut off House Elf privileges the week prior in order to 'build character'), as the Gryffindors had certain objections to this new organizational scheme.

"Seven seventy-one. What's the problem this time?" Milo asked distractedly from a couch. He was one of a very few number of Gryffindors who did not care one whit for Quidditch, nor, consequently, even half a whit for the logistics of its players' skill grinding. While they fretted about inconsequential matters, Milo was busy performing magic upon an ordinary-looking bucket.

"Snape," Harry spat through clenched teeth. It said something of the general morale of House Gryffindor that not even Hermione was willing to call out his failure to prefix 'Professor' to the Headmaster's name, "has the pitch rotating between all of the houses."

Milo narrowed his eyes suspiciously.

"Hold your hippogriffs," Harry said. "Fifty-four."

"What's the problem with the rotation?" Milo asked, scratching the Eye of Boccob onto the cheap tin bucket.

"Well," Harry said, "today, Hufflepuff has the pitch. Tomorrow it's Slytherin. Next it's Ravenclaw."

"Then Gryffindor?" Milo asked.

"No," Harry said. "Then Slytherin. Then Gryffindor. Then Slytherin again. Then Ravenclaw. Then Slytherin."

"Ah," Milo said in understanding as he put the finishing touches on the Wavy Eyebrow of Boccob. "Well, it's a problem easily solved."

"How do you figure?" Harry asked, sitting dejectedly beside him on the sofa.

Milo held the bucket on the ground with both feet and grabbed the handle with his hands."We break into Snape's office, steal some Polyjuice, kidnap the entire Slytherin team, and you play in disguise." With a hefty pull, he yanked the handle clean off the bucket. "Of course," he added, "we'll have to kill them afterwards, or they'll talk."

"You're kidding, right?" Harry asked, slightly apprehensively.

"'Course," Milo said. "We can just steal their memories after. I know a guy." The Memory Charm was yet another example of Arcane Magic and Wanded Magic diverging. If Milo ever wanted to erase someone's memory, he'd have to first become a mighty Bard (as if) and even then could only modify up to five minutes of memory per day—and that was only because he had, for some reason, prioritized Charisma over Constitution at character creation. Milo was still kicking himself over that particularly inspired decision.

Those goons at the Ministry, on the other hand, could literally just wave their wands and magically erase or alter, as far as Milo could tell, any amount of memory they wanted. Poof, gone.

"Ha," Harry said flatly. "Ha, ha." He glanced at Milo, who was replacing the handle with a leather strap. "That looks like a Quidditch chinstrap," he said.

"That's hardly surprising," Milo responded, threading one end of the chinstrap through a hole he'd drilled in the bucket.

Harry frowned. "That is a Quidditch chinstrap."

"Yup," Milo said.

Harry's emerald green eyes narrowed. "That's my Quidditch chinstrap."

"Yup," Milo said. "But don't worry; you won't be needing yours anymore."

"Oh?" Harry asked in a dangerous tone of voice. "And why is that?"

"I overheard Malfoy at breakfast. Snape's going to ban safety gear for future matches. He says the rate of serious injuries has been so low since the gear was introduced that it's unnecessary."

"But the rate is only low because we're wearing padding!" Harry said.

"Snape's not entirely unreasonable," Milo said. "He said that any players who are new to the team this year will still wear padding."

Harry frowned. "That doesn't sound too... Oh." After the Petrification of the majority of the Slytherin Quidditch team, almost every single player was a new recruit. Harry punched the scarlet couch in frustration. Slytherin was the only team with new players this year. "This is ridiculous!"

"Then there's good news," Milo said. "Snape's also going to be introducing a complaint-and-suggestion box. Have a complaint or suggestion for the administration, you write it on a slip of parchment and drop it in the box."

Harry blinked. "Seriously?" he asked. "That doesn't sound like Snape at all. That's actually a good idea." He frowned. "What's the catch?"

"Remember last year when Hannah discovered a secret, slippery passage that dumps you in the lake?"

"Yeah. First years have been using it as a waterslide."

"Guess where the box empties into." Milo wrapped the bucket-with-chinstrap up in thick brown postal paper. "Mind if I borrow Hedge Witch?"

"Hedwig."

"Is there any other kind?" Milo asked.

"What?"

"Of wig, that is. Any other kind of wig."

"What are you talking about?"

"Well, it's not like you could have a foot wig or a shoulder wig, could you? I mean, every wig I've ever heard of goes on your head. So calling him—"

"Her."

"—Head Wig seems a bit redundant." Milo scribbled 'COG, THE BURROW, UNITED KINGDOM, PRIME MATERIAL PLANE' on the package.

Harry sighed, covering his face with his hands. "Yes," he said. "Yes, you can borrow Hedwig."

"Cool," Milo said. "Oh, and before I forget—" he tossed Harry a heavy sack that clinked in a deliciously metallic manner. "That's the first quarter. I'll get you the rest by June."

Harry blinked in genuine surprise and stared at the money.

"How did you— no, I suppose I probably don't want to know."

Milo looked around the room suspiciously. Everyone's attention was focused complaining ineffectually about Snape's latest announcement.

"Meet me in the War Room in twenty," he whispered, tucking the wrapped bucket into his belt for later. "Spread the word, but don't all leave as one group."

"I know the drill," Harry said.

Twenty-odd minutes later, Harry, Ron, and Hermione filed one by one into the empty classroom Milo had appropriated behind the tree he'd created last year. In addition to being concealed and inconvenient to get to, the room had a few magical defenses Milo had set up. The most powerful defense, the one that would absolutely guarantee their privacy for the indefinite future, was the hastily-scrawled sign that hung from the door, reading: REMEDIAL DIVINATIONS.

"Fifteen-thousand, five-hundred and fifty-six," Milo said.

"Zero," Hermione replied.

"Fifty-five," Harry said.

Everyone stared at Ron.

"Ah," he said. "A hundred and six? No, wait, um..."

Hermione and Harry moved their hands in the general direction of their wands. Milo shook his hands out of his sleeves.

"A billion!" Ron said. "I know I haven't used that one yet. It's just hard keeping track."

Everybody relaxed. Since Death Eaters had used Polyjuice to disguise themselves as Gryffindors, paranoia had been running high—paranoia actively encouraged by Milo himself. Paranoia was the last and best defence against the DM (Detrimental Meddler). To that end, they'd created their code: upon meeting another member of their group, say a number. Any number, as long as it wasn't one you'd already used. The idea was that any infiltrator listening to them would either think it was an elaborate code and waste valuable time trying to crack it, or that they would, in their confusion, reuse a number. It was far from perfect, but it was the best Milo had been able to think up that would be simple enough for them all to get right reliably.

"We have a Defence exam tomorrow," Hermione said. "We should all be revising. Why did you call us here?"

"I think it's been long enough that we can be pretty much certain," Milo said. "The Heir of Slytherin—or, at least the relevant one—is in Lucius' camp. The only open question is who."

"How do you figure?" Hermione asked.

"Other than that it's blindingly obvious?" Ron scoffed. "The Heir is as Slytherin is can be, Lucius is as Slytherin as can be. The Heir hates Muggle borns, Lucius hates Muggle borns. If so, fact-oh."

Hermione chortled under her breath.

"What?" Ron asked defensively.

Harry leaned over to Ron and whispered, "it's ipso facto, Ron."

"But that sounds like a spell," he said. "Is it a spell?" Ron's face paled slightly. "What if it's a spell of persuasion," he said, "and that's why, whenever anyone says it, what they said sounds so reasonable!"

"Moving right along," Milo said, trying to regain control of the conversation. Honestly, it was like herding cats sometimes. "Ron's already laid out the core of the evidence, but there's a bit more to it. Snape is Lucius's right-hand man in Hogwarts, and as soon as Snape took over, the attacks miraculously stopped."

Harry frowned. "You mean you don't think the attacks were directed at Muggle borns?"

"Of course they weren't," Milo said. "Slytherin's monster took out basically the entire Slytherin Quidditch team, and they were pretty much all pure- or half-blooded, and Muggle-haters to boot. That's not exactly behaviour consistent with an agenda of ridding the world of Muggle borns, is it?"

"I always sort of figured the monster was going for some Muggle borns, but kept running into other people instead," Harry said.

"And what," asked Ron, "after Petrifying all witnesses, it just gave up and ran back into its hole? No, I'm starting to think Milo's right. If the monster wanted to get Muggle borns, there's not much anyone could do to stop it."

"How long do you think it would stay secret if it did that?" Hermione asked. "People would discover it pretty quickly if it gave up on stealth altogether."

"Yeah," Ron said, "but then what? I mean, it took McGonagall in a fair fight. McGonagall!"

Milo coughed involuntarily. He hadn't told them that it was largely his fault McGonagall had been Petrified, and had no intention of doing so.

"Maybe it just can't tell the difference?" Hermione said. "It could be that all humans look pretty much the same to it. I mean, if it Petrifies with a look, it probably hasn't had much in the way of social interaction."

"Could be," Milo said. "But then I doubt Slytherin would have picked it to be his monster with the specific aim of ridding the school of undesirables. Now, what is it that Draco always says?"

"'He started it, Professor!'" Ron suggested.

"'When my father hears about this, Potter, he'll—'" Harry said, then frowned. "I don't know what comes next. He always gets cut off somehow. I wonder if he even knows what his father will do."

"'Father always said that Dumbledore was the worst thing that ever happened to this place,'" Hermione said.

"In one," Milo said.

"So you think Dumbledore was the target, then?"

"The entire old administration," Milo said. "Lucius couldn't get Dumbledore out because he had too many friends on the board and in the Ministry. There's too much respect for him. But by Petrifying an entire group of students right under Dumbledore's nose, he disgraced him. The fact that the students all had rich, influential parents likely didn't hurt. The Heir got Dumbledore sacked and nearly killed McGonagall, leaving Snape in charge, and poof! No more attacks. How long do you think it'll be till they give him a medal for saving the school? Order of Murlynd, or whatever. So the Heir of Slytherin is probably Lucius, Snape, Draco, or another Slytherin."

"Or another disguised Death Eater," Harry said. "Or one of the same ones from before, which you let go."

"Why did you let them go, anyway?" Ron asked.

Milo shrugged uncomfortably. It had seemed to make so much sense at the time. Clearly, this world was dulling his edge. He blamed homework. "I still haven't had any luck scrying the Heir of Slytherin, despite Hermione's clever workaround. We might have to resort to more conventional methods to determine who it is, precisely."

"What if there is no Heir of Slytherin?" Hermione suggested, at the same time that Ron said "Bet it's Draco."

"What do you mean, Hermione?" Harry asked. "If there's no heir, then who's controlling the monster?"

Hermione shrugged. "What if it doesn't have to be Slytherin's actual, literal heir? What if access to the Chamber of Secrets isn't based off of what you are, but what you know?"

"A password, then?" Milo suggested. "Handed down the family line?"

"Could be, or even the directions. You don't need a password if nobody else can even find the place."

"I don't know, Hermione," Ron said. "I think you'd need to do more than just hide it. Fred and George have found dozens of 'secret' passages and rooms over the years. Nobody's found the Chamber. It can't just be hidden."

"Point," Hermione acknowledged. "But regardless, what I'm getting at is it doesn't have to be his actual heir. Just someone who knows what Slytherin knew. That's why Milo's magic hasn't been able to find him or her. He's been targeting the Heir of Slytherin specifically."

"So it could be anyone?" Harry said. "Anyone at all?"

Harry's words hung in the air as everyone realized how hopeless the situation was. They'd come all this way, and they still had seemingly nothing to go on.

"A Parselmouth," Milo said suddenly. "Whoever's controlling the Monster is a Parselmouth. It spoke to McGonagall and me in Parseltongue. And Harry was the only one who heard it speak in the Duelling Club last month."

"How'd you know it was Parseltongue?" Ron asked.

"Maaaaagic," Milo said, wiggling his fingers in the air. "It's almost as if we were all wizards or something."

Hermione coughed.

"And witch," Milo added quickly. "Wizards and witch."

"So..." Ron said thoughtfully. "Any way we can sort out who in this school is secretly a Parselmouth?"

Milo shrugged. "Who cares?" he said. "I think if there's one point Hermione's made, it's that we're focussing all of our attention on the wrong person. What I say we do is we find the monster, and hit it with everything we've got. Our mysterious foe loses his cat's paw, and either gives up or comes out into the open to do it himself."

"And what have we got, exactly?" Hermione asked. "The three of us can just about manage Stunners and Shield charms, but I doubt either of those will be much good against a giant, evil monster that we can presume is resistant to magic."

"Fair point," Milo said.

"That one went a little fast for me," Harry confessed. "Why do we know it's resistant to magic?"

"Because McGonagall transfigured knives and fired them at it," Hermione said. "The knives were real, physical objects, and only had to contend with the monster's physical defenses. If she could have used magic, she would have Stunned it—or killed it outright. The Forbidden Curses are only Forbidden against humans, after all."

"Reeeeeeally," Milo said thoughtfully.

"No," Hermione said forcefully.

"But—"

"No. No mind-slaved armies of unicorns or goblins or acromantulas."

"What I don't understand is why the Ministry hasn't combed this place with hit wizards or people from the Department of Regulation and Control of Magical Creatures or something," Harry said.

"Probably Lucius keeping them out," Hermione answered. "Pulling strings at the Ministry."

Milo snorted. "He should grow a goatee. He's beginning to remind me of someone back home." He wondered how Myra (City of light! City of Magic!) was faring in his absence, and realized it had been over a month since he'd thought of home. He was surprised at how little he missed it. They didn't have anything like Every Flavoured Beans, there. Just the thought sent his mouth watering.

Idly, he popped an Every-Flavoured Bean into his mouth. He didn't recognize the sharp, tangy flavour—he hardly ever did, barely knowing the flavour of any real foods to compare it with—but enjoyed it nonetheless, if only for the novelty.

"What do we know about Slytherin's monster?" Harry asked.

"Loads," Milo said. "But somehow, not enough to identify it in any reference book. Believe me; I've tried. It speaks Parseltongue, so it's probably some kind of snake; it has fangs and venom, fitting with the snake theme; it's resistant to magic; it can Petrify with a look, but it's not a Medusa. Oh, and Mordenkainen assures me it smells terrible. Turns out there aren't many things that can cause Petrification—your kind, not mine—on a gaze attack around here. They mostly just kill people, or turn them to stone."

They spent most of the next three hours debating the possible identity of Slytherin's Monster, all without making any progress. Eventually, fed up with the futility of it, they gave up and headed to the Great Hall for dinner.

Milo lagged behind the rest of the group, frustrated. He couldn't believe how little progress they'd made. That he'd made.

It was this place. It had dulled his edge. There was no other explanation. Between the pointless classes and the delicious food and the soft mattresses, he'd lost sight of what was important.

He did have one more clue he could follow. He knew that, but he'd felt strangely resistant to the idea. The feeling was a stranger to him, but, when it came down to it, so were most.

He left the group and made for the Hospital Wing. He waited outside the door behind a suit of armour for a few minutes until Madam Pomfrey left for her evening meal.

Milo crept into the room, surprised to find it absent of one of its most permanent residents. Even his bags were gone. Neville Longbottom, it seemed, had managed to make it a whole day without getting some kind of injury.

He found McGonagall where he left her on the hospital bed, his mirror still clutched in her hand.

Milo gently placed one hand over her injury, and, with the other, drew his other mirror from his belt. This one, of highly-polished silver, had a far more specialized purpose than looking around corners without risking a headshot.

"Scry," he whispered, gazing intently into the mirror.

His reflection vanished from the mirror's surface. For an instant, Milo got the impression of slick green scales in a dark room. A moment later it was gone, the surface of the mirror broken as if someone had taken a light mace to it.

"Guess I should have expected that," he muttered, remembering what had happened to his Arcane Eye. "Mending," he muttered, and the cracks were gone as if they had never been.

It was all so frustrating. This monster seemed to be resistant to Milo's best methods of magical sleuthing. He hadn't had any luck finding any of the missing students, either. Circle Dance and Scrying had both failed outright, as if they'd been blocked. It seemed the Death Eaters had found some way to prevent their victims from being located magically. Maybe Milo really did need remedial Divinations.

But if you couldn't find someone with magic, how were you supposed to do it?

o—o—o—o

"We got one," Hannigan said, slamming the phone into the receiver triumphantly. "Patrol officer up in London made a positive ID on one 'Amycus Carrow' at a supermarket. Tailed him back to a residence he seems holed up. He's ours now; all we have to do is go and get him." It had been a simple, yet time-consuming, matter to cross-reference the wizard's histories on the 'Wizarding War' with case files from the '81—most of which were dropped under rather suspect scenarios—and come up with a list of twenty-odd suspected murderers. Now that they had relatively concrete evidence of magic in the form of the Daily Prophet's moving pictures, Hannigan had been getting a few of his friends still sore from the 1981 murders on board with the investigation. They'd been unofficially passing hints on possible positions of the culprits. Their books on the wizard's history implied that some of them had already been tried in secret wizard court and sent to a secret wizard prison, but that most of them were still at large. Apparently the wizards' judicial system was even more porous than the regular one.

"A supermarket?" Fiona asked. "Really?" She had a hard time imagining an evil wizard at a place as mundane as a supermarket, but, on the other hand, she supposed everyone had to eat.

"Was he the one that did the Petersons?" Travis asked, flipping through his notebook. "And the Lancasters. And the Walkers, too." He gave out a low whistle, reading the notes he'd made from the wizards' books. "He got a bunch of their folk, too."

"My counterpart in London wants to go in with a Firearms Unit and arrest him, but I persuaded him to wait for us. Get your coats on, both of you. You've been reading up on their abilities," Hannigan said to Fiona as they suited up. "How would you take him?"

"A high-powered rifle from three streets away," Fiona said seriously.

"Perhaps I should have specified," Hannigan said. "In this hypothetical scenario, do remember you're a copper."

"Then I'd shoot him and take the fall for it after. They have spells that kill, spells that control, spells that torture, and spells that protect."

"Even from bullets?" Travis asked as they left the station into the bitter cold and heavy snow.

"No clue," Fiona said. "The spellbook didn't say. Frankly, I don't think they even considered it. They don't seem to think of us as much of a threat. Still, we should assume they can."

Hannigan scratched his chin. He hadn't shaved in days, and Fiona doubted he'd slept more than a few hours a night, either. She couldn't remember the last time she'd seen him without a mug of cheap, black coffee in hand.

"Don't we have anything going for us?" he asked.

"Some," Fiona said. "They need a wand to do any magic at all, so if we can keep him from drawing, he's only as dangerous as you or I."

Travis made a derisive snort. "That I doubt," he said. "As dangerous as me, maybe, but I bet he doesn't know kung-fu."

"Aikido," Fiona corrected him, "and we shouldn't assume he doesn't. Also, he needs to be able to speak to cast, and it seems to take a few seconds to get a spell off."

"So it's like a gun and body armour," Travis said, "but a little worse? What's so scary about that? We get the blue berets to toss a handful of flashbangs through the window, daze the people inside too much to even think about bloody witchcraft, batter down the door and cuff everyone in a Hallowe'en costume."

"I'm not finished yet," Fiona said. "They can also teleport."

Hannigan spat coffee onto the snow.

"Like on bleeding Star Trek?" he asked.

"Pretty much," Fiona said. "To them, its equivalent to getting a driver's license. Worst of all, it didn't say if they needed a wand or not to do it."

"Well that's just bloody great," he said. "How the bloody hell do we bloody arrest a person who can just bloody teleport out of the bloody station?"

"We can't," Fiona said simply. "Ergo, a high-powered rifle from three streets away."

"Or we give him an incentive," Travis suggested. "A reason to do what we want him to do. To not leave."

"What do we have that he wants?" Hannigan asked. "He can just beam himself away and come back with half a dozen of his guys and make us all forget. Or kill us, more likely."

"Secrecy," Travis said. "We tell him if he does anything spooky, we send everything we have to the Guardian. Evil wizard or no, he wouldn't want that."

Fiona gave a low whistle. "Are we really prepared to do that?" she asked. "That could be big. Like, world-changing big."

"Ethical debate later," Hannigan said as they arrived at his car. "First, we have to nick him."